<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Datasets xmlns="http://rs.tdwg.org/UBIF/2006/" xmlns:u="http://rs.tdwg.org/UBIF/2006/" xmlns:ues="http://rs.tdwg.org/UBIF/2006/EnumSpecs/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://rs.tdwg.org/UBIF/2006/ ../SDD.xsd http://rs.tdwg.org/UBIF/2006/EnumSpecs/ UBIF_EnumSpecs.xsd">
  <TechnicalMetadata created="9999-01-01T00:00:00">
    <!--This should be changed to the true current date (e.g. 2004-08-13T00:00:00), not possible with standard xslt 1.0!-->
    <Generator name="DiversitySchemaTools Version 0.5. Copyright (c) G. Hagedorn 2006." version="0.5"/>
  </TechnicalMetadata>
  <Dataset xml:lang="en-us">
    <Representation>
      <Label>Enumerated value concepts for application building</Label>
      <Detail>This document is generated by an xslt script from the enumerations present in the following schema: "Unified Biosciences Information Framework (UBIF) 1.1". Enumerations are converted to SDD descriptive concepts (enumerated values are represented by concept states). The html report generated for these values / concept states is intended for documentation and to improve discussion and correction of errors (please comment on http://wiki.tdwg.org/twiki/bin/view/UBIF/EnumeratedValues). The xml representation follows the general conventions of UBIF documents and may be easier to import or integrate into user interfaces than the schema itself. This is especially true for SDD documents, where a large part of the terminology is provided in the form of data documents by the experts of a given knowledge domain. This document can be used side-by-side as schema-defined terminology with user-defined terminology.</Detail>
    </Representation>
    <DescriptiveConcepts>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="RevisionStatusEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>RevisionStatus</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing the revision status as assessed by creators or editors or objects. It may apply to an entire data set as well as to individual objects (a specimen, a taxon name, a description, etc.). Exact semantics are defined only for the first and the last two categories. The semantics of the intermediate levels (1 to 5) may be chosen freely by the user (and associated with the actual, project dependend workflow, e.g. 'draft', 'review', 'approved', 'stable'). The added semantics should, however, conserve the order of revision status values. If, for example, three revision steps are planned (2 intermediate, reaching FullyRevised on third), it is recommended to use RevisionLevel2, RevisionLevel4, FullyRevised.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Unrevised">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Unrevised</Label>
              <Detail>The data have been input, but no separate revision was performed.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="RevisionLevel1">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Revision level 1 of 5</Label>
              <Detail>For example, in a collection less than ca. 20 % of the data are revised, or on a single object only a plausibility check has been performed.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="RevisionLevel2">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Revision level 2 of 5</Label>
              <Detail>For example, in a collection ca. 41-60 % of the data are revised, or on a single object the data are compared carefully with the source.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="RevisionLevel3">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Revision level 3 of 5</Label>
              <Detail>For example, ca. 41-60 % of the data are revised.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="RevisionLevel4">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Revision level 4 of 5</Label>
              <Detail>For example, ca. 61-80 % of the data are revised.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="RevisionLevel5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Revision level 5 of 5</Label>
              <Detail>For example, more than 80% revised (but not yet completed).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="FullyRevised">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Revision completed</Label>
              <Detail>The data are completely revised given the available time and the goals set for the project. This does not necessarily imply that the data are complete and perfectly revised in a scientific sense.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Deprecated">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Deprecated</Label>
              <Detail>An object concept should no longer be used, but is not deleted because external data depend on it. This revision status applies, e.g. to definitions in shared descriptive terminologies.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="ExpertiseLevelEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>ExpertiseLevel</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing the expertise exprected or required from human consumers of data or services. Values are restricted to integer values from 0 to 5. 0 is defined as unspecified level, and 1 to 5 indicates expertise from schoolchildren to taxonomic expert. See the description of the values for recommendations for interpreting and choosing the expert level.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="ExpertiseLevel0">
            <Representation>
              <Label>0 = Unspecified expertise level</Label>
              <Detail>Use this if the expertise level of can not be assessed (e. g. when exporting data) or is considered irrelevant.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ExpertiseLevel1">
            <Representation>
              <Label>1 = Elementary school (year 1 to 6)</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ExpertiseLevel2">
            <Representation>
              <Label>2 = Middle school (year 7 to 10)</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ExpertiseLevel3">
            <Representation>
              <Label>3 = High school (year 11 above) and general public</Label>
              <Detail>When addressing this level specialized terminology or jargon should be avoided.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ExpertiseLevel4">
            <Representation>
              <Label>4 = University students or (partly) trained staff</Label>
              <Detail>This level uses specialized terminology, but avoids or explains problematic terms.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ExpertiseLevel5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>5 = Experts</Label>
              <Detail>This level uses the full range of terminology</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="ResourceTypeEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>ResourceType</Label>
          <Detail>This enumeration is identical with the DCMI Type Vocabulary (http: //dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/, as of 6/2004), except that an additional type "Other" has been added. Its purpose is to provide a framework of broad media or resource type terms, without the technical detail provided by the large number of MIME types. The annotations are largely based on those from the DublinCore metadata initiative vocabulary.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Collection">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Collection</Label>
              <Detail>A collection is an aggregation of items. The term collection means that the resource is described as a group; its parts may be separately described and navigated.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Dataset">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Dataset</Label>
              <Detail>A dataset is information encoded in a defined structure (for example, lists, tables, and databases), intended to be useful for direct machine processing.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Event">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Event</Label>
              <Detail>An event is a non-persistent, time-based occurrence. Metadata for an event provides descriptive information that is the basis for discovery of the purpose, location, duration, responsible agents, and links to related events and resources. The resource of type event may not be retrievable if the described instantiation has expired or is yet to occur. Examples - exhibition, web-cast, conference, workshop, open-day, performance, battle, trial, wedding, tea-party, conflagration.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Image">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Image</Label>
              <Detail>An image is a primarily symbolic visual representation other than text. For example - images and photographs of physical objects, paintings, prints, drawings, other images and graphics, animations and moving pictures, film, diagrams, maps, musical notation. Note that image may include both electronic and physical representations.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="InteractiveResource">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Interactive Resource</Label>
              <Detail>An interactive resource is a resource which requires interaction from the user to be understood, executed, or experienced. For example - forms on web pages, applets, multimedia learning objects, chat services, virtual reality.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="MovingImage">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Moving Image (Video)</Label>
              <Detail>A series of visual representations that, when shown in succession, impart an impression of motion. Examples of moving images are: animations, movies, television programs, videos, zoetropes, or visual output from a simulation. Comment: Instances of the type "Moving Image" must also be describable as instances of the broader type "Image".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="PhysicalObject">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Physical Object</Label>
              <Detail>An inanimate, three-dimensional object or substance. For example -- a computer, the great pyramid, a sculpture. Note that digital representations of, or surrogates for, these things should use Image, Text or one of the other types.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Service">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Service</Label>
              <Detail>A service is a system that provides one or more functions of value to the end-user. Examples include: a photocopying service, a banking service, an authentication service, interlibrary loans, a Z39.50 or Web server.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Software">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Software</Label>
              <Detail>Software is a computer program in source or compiled form which may be available for installation non-transiently on another machine. For software which exists only to create an interactive environment, use interactive instead.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Sound">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Sound</Label>
              <Detail>A sound is a resource whose content is primarily intended to be rendered as audio. For example - a music playback file format, an audio compact disc, and recorded speech or sounds.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="StillImage">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Still Image</Label>
              <Detail>A static visual representation. Examples of still images are: paintings, drawings, graphic designs, plans and maps. Comment: Recommended best practice is to assign the type "Text" to images of textual materials. Instances of the type "Still Image" must also be describable as instances of the broader type "Image".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Text">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Text</Label>
              <Detail>A text is a resource whose content is primarily words for reading. For example - books, letters, dissertations, poems, newspapers, articles, archives of mailing lists. Note that facsimiles or images of texts are still of the genre text. Text may contain embedded still image illustrations, e. g., formatted html pages.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Other">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Other</Label>
              <Detail>Use this category if the resource does not seem to fit into any of the categories provided above.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TelephoneDeviceEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TelephoneDevice</Label>
          <Detail>Kind of phone number: voice, fax, mobile, pager, modem. These enumerated values are identical with vCard 3.0 flags (several of which can be added to a single phone number; to represent this in the UBIF interface duplicate the phone number itself!)</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Voice">
            <Representation>
              <Label>voice phone number</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Fax">
            <Representation>
              <Label>fax number</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Mobile">
            <Representation>
              <Label>mobile phone number</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Modem">
            <Representation>
              <Label>modem number</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Pager">
            <Representation>
              <Label>pager number</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="Rating1to5Enum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>Rating1to5</Label>
          <Detail>Enumeration restricted to integer values from 1 to 5, indicating an arbitrary rating (meaning, e. g., 1 = disagree strongly, 2 = rather disagree, 3 = neutral or undecided, 4 = rather agree, 5 = agree strongly). This enumeration is of limited usefulness and could be replaced by an restriction on integer, but using the enumeration the semantics of agreement/disagreement or positive/negative rating can be communicated in a culture-neutral way (in German 1 is generally considered best and 5 worst, in English 1 worst, 5 best...).</Detail>
          <Label xml:lang="de">Rating1to5</Label>
          <Detail xml:lang="de">Aufzählung von ganzzahligen Werten zwischen 0 u. 5 für beliebige Bewertungsskalen. Beispiel für Interpretation der 5 Werte: 1 = ablehnend, 2 = eher ablehnend, 3 =neutral oder unentschieden, 4 = eher zustimmend, 5 = zustimmend)</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Rating0of5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Rating "0"</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">0</Label>
              <Detail>Undecided (not yet rated).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Rating1of5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Rating "1"</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">1</Label>
              <Detail>For example, "disagree strongly", or "very poor".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Rating2of5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Rating "2"</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">2</Label>
              <Detail>For example, "rather disagree", or "poor".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Rating3of5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Rating "3"</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">3</Label>
              <Detail>For example, "neutral", "average", "undecided".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Rating4of5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Rating "4"</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">4</Label>
              <Detail>For example, "rather agree", or "good".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Rating5of5">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Rating "5"</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">5</Label>
              <Detail>For example, "agree strongly", or "very good".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TextDirectionalityEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TextDirectionality</Label>
          <Detail>Values are ltr (left to right), rtl (right to left). Compare CSS2 and the XHTML 2.0 bi-directional text module. Note: A future UBIF version may also include lro/rlo = left-right-overide/right-left-overide, if this is found to be necessary.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="ltr">
            <Representation>
              <Label>left-to-right text direction (e.g., English)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">ltr</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="rtl">
            <Representation>
              <Label>right-to-left text direction (e.g., Arabic)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">rtl</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="StringFormattingTypeEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>StringFormattingType</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing whether and which kind of inline formatting may be contained in a text literal (plain, inline-entity-encoded, html-level-entity-encoded). In the absence of an attribute providing further specification, most UBIF text elements may contain "inline" entity-escaped formatting! (Other standards: ~=atom:title/@type)</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="plain">
            <Representation>
              <Label>plain, unformatted text</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">plain</Label>
              <Detail>The element contains plain text with no entity escaped html. The entire text will contain the same format, i.e. it can contain not superscript, subscript or italicized parts. Example: "Mg2Cl &gt; 10mMol" (xml-entities like greater-than are still entity escaped!). Other standards: atom:title/@type=text.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="inline">
            <Representation>
              <Label>formatted text using selected html inline elements</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">inline</Label>
              <Detail>The element contains html formatting from an enumerated list of html inline formatting commands: strong, em, b, i, sub, sup, br. Other html commands (including inline formatting like a and img) are not recognized. Example: "Mg&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Cl &gt; 10mMol". Note: the constrained list of formats enables processors with limited implementation cost to render the formatting in other formats than the html-family.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="html">
            <Representation>
              <Label>formatted text using html elements</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">html</Label>
              <Detail>The element contains html formatting commands for an enumerated list of html inline formatting commands: strong, em, b, i, sub, sup, br. Other html commands (including inline formatting like a and img) are not recognized. Example: "Mg&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Cl &gt; 10mMol". Other standards: atom:title/@type=html. Note: atom also provides a value "xhtml", in which case the element content is directly full xhtml (i.e. contains mixed content). Such mixed content formatting was provided in early proposals of UBIF, but was rejected because it created significantly increased implementation cost in applications, including xslt in general and xml-database conversions. See EncodedFormattingProposal.zip for further information.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="MeasurementUnitPrefixEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>MeasurementUnitPrefix</Label>
          <Detail>Multiplication factor prefixes used in the scientific SI system (T, G, M, k, h, c, m, µ, n, p, f, a).</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Tera">
            <Representation>
              <Label>tera</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">T</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of 12. Example: TW, terawatt.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Tera</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">T</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch 12.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E12</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Giga">
            <Representation>
              <Label>giga</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">G</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of 9. Example: GV, gigavolt.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Giga</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">G</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch 9.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E9</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Mega">
            <Representation>
              <Label>mega</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">M</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of 6. Example: MW, megawatt.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mega </Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">M</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch 6.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E6</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="kilo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>kilo</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">k</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 1000. Example: kg, kilogram.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Kilo</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">k</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 1000.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>1000</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="hecto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>hecto</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">h</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 100. Example: hPa, hectopascal.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Hekto</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">h</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 100.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>100</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="deca">
            <Representation>
              <Label>deca</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">da</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10. Example: daL, decaliter.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Deka</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">da</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="noprefix">
            <Representation>
              <Label>(none)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">-</Label>
              <Detail>No prefix, denoting factor or 1. Example: g, gram.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">(keine)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">-</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Kein Prefix, entspricht einem Faktor von 1.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>1</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="deci">
            <Representation>
              <Label>deci</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">d</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting a factor of 0.1. Example: dm, decimeter.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Dezi</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">d</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 0.1.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>0.1</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="centi">
            <Representation>
              <Label>centi</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">c</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting a factor of 0.01. Example: cm, centimeter.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Centi</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">c</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 0.01.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>0.01</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="milli">
            <Representation>
              <Label>milli</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">m</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of -3. Example: mg, milligram.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Milli</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">m</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch -3.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E-3</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="micro">
            <Representation>
              <Label>micro</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">µ</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of -6. Example: µg, microgram.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mikro</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">µ</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch -6.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E-6</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="nano">
            <Representation>
              <Label>nano</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">n</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of -9. Example: ng, nanogram.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Nano</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">n</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch -9.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E-9</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="pico">
            <Representation>
              <Label>pico</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">p</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of -12. Example: pmol, picomol.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Piko</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">p</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch -12.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E-12</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="femto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>femto</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">f</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of -15. Example: fm, femtometer.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Femto</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">f</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch -15.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E-15</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="atto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>atto</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">a</Label>
              <Detail>Prefix of measurement units, denoting 10 to the power of -18. Example: attotesla.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Atto</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">a</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Prefix wissenschaftlicher Maßeinheiten, entspricht einem Faktor von 10 hoch -18.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:Factor>10E-18</ues:Factor>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="StatisticalMeasurementScaleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>StatisticalMeasurementScale</Label>
          <Detail>In statistical analysis it is often vital to know some basic properties of the values that are being analyzed. Some of these properties can be summarized in the form of a measurement scale. Higher scales can always be analyzed under the assumptions of a lower scale (ordinal data can be analyzed as nominal, ratio as interval).</Detail>
          <Label xml:lang="x-internal">StatisticalMeasurementScale</Label>
          <Detail xml:lang="x-internal">In principal it would be desirable to define values in small enumerations, and then the supersets as:  xs:union memberTypes="QuantitativeMeasurementScaleEnum CategoricalMeasurementScaleEnum"/. Compare other comments for restriction-problems Xerces has with this.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Nominal">
            <Representation>
              <Label>nominal</Label>
              <Detail>unordered categorical states (DELTA character type 'UM')</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Ordinal">
            <Representation>
              <Label>ordinal</Label>
              <Detail>ordered categorical states (DELTA character type 'OM'). Unless a separate tree defines more specific ordering, the order is assumed to be linear in the sequence in which the categories are enumerated in their definition.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Interval">
            <Representation>
              <Label>interval</Label>
              <Detail>real numeric (= floating point) values, where 0 is an arbitrarily defined point. As a consequence, ratios are undefined and only the intervals between values can be analyzed. Example: Temperature in °C or °F.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Ratio">
            <Representation>
              <Label>ratio</Label>
              <Detail>real numeric (= floating point) values (DELTA: type 'RN'), where 0 is an objective point and ratios can thus be analyzed. Example: length measurements. Most measures belong into this category and it is acceptable to assume the 'ratio' scale when importing DELTA legacy data.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="QuantitativeMeasurementScaleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>QuantitativeMeasurementScale</Label>
          <Detail>Those values from StatisticalMeasurementScaleEnum addressing numerical data ('ratio' and 'interval').  
Note: Occasionally "integer" or "cardinal" (versus real numbers) are also considered part of the measurement scale. This should be avoided because: a) All combinations of interval/ratio and discrete/continous are possible. b) The important distinction is whether a measurement is based on a continuous or discrete scale. Although in most cases this is equivalent with integer versus real numbers, it is not necessarily so. An ANOVA will report false significance not only when values come from "1, 2, 3 and 4", but also when they come from "1.2, 2.4, 3.6 and 4.8".</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Interval</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Interval" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ratio</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Ratio" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="CategoricalMeasurementScaleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>CategoricalMeasurementScale</Label>
          <Detail>Those values from StatisticalMeasurementScaleEnum addressing categorical data ('nominal' and 'ordinal').</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Nominal</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Nominal" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ordinal</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Ordinal" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="DataStatusEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>DataStatus</Label>
          <Detail>Status values (examples: "unknown", "not applicable") identify standardized reasons why data are missing. Alternative names are  'missing data indicators',  'special states', 'Null-values'. The annotation labels of the values can be freely changed as long as the semantics are preserved.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="ToBeChecked">
            <Representation>
              <Label>To be checked</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">!</Label>
              <Detail>Explicit indicator to revisit data later. This may occur when data are missing (known to exist, but not at hand for entering) or together with data (check  entered data against additional information source).</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:BasicStatus>ToBeCoded</ues:BasicStatus>
              <ues:InformationInSource>ProbablyExists</ues:InformationInSource>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ToBeIgnored">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Not to be recorded (a decision was made not enter data)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">ø</Label>
              <Detail>(No DELTA equivalent exists. Implemented in Lucid 3 as "scope out".)</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:BasicStatus>NotToBeCoded</ues:BasicStatus>
              <ues:InformationInSource>ProbablyExists</ues:InformationInSource>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="NotApplicable">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Not applicable (data are assumed to be impossible to exist)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">-</Label>
              <Detail>The character has been studied, but is not applicable. Example are situations where the character cannot possibly exists (e. g. leaf-tip in a leaf-less plant) or where the method is unable to measure the current situation (e. g. a growth rate if available space is used before the time defined in the method). In the first situation it may be desirable to create a character dependency definition, making the scoring of individual characters no longer necessary. (Note: the DELTA equivalent is the '-'-state.)</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:BasicStatus>CannotBeCoded</ues:BasicStatus>
              <ues:InformationInSource>CannotExist</ues:InformationInSource>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="DataUnavailable">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Data unavailable (could not be obtained despite that an effort was made)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">?</Label>
              <Detail>The character has been studied and information has been searched, but not found. Use this to indicate that coding attempts should stop, perhaps until the next major revision. If data are currently unavailable, but attempts should continue, use '# = to be checked' instead. Compare also "not interpretable" if information found that is not interpretable. (Note: the DELTA equivalent is normally the 'U', but 'U' may also be used differently.)</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:BasicStatus>CannotBeCoded</ues:BasicStatus>
              <ues:InformationInSource>DoesNotExist</ues:InformationInSource>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="NotInterpretable">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Not interpretable (data known to exist, but interpretation considered too uncertain).</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">#</Label>
              <Detail>The character has been studied and information has been found, but is impossible to score because the information is not interpretable under the current terminology. Using this status value warns collaborators that some information has already been studied (a specific annotation text accompanying the status value is recommend). Examples for using 'not interpretable': terms used in the source are undefined and cannot be guessed, the information in the source is contradictory, the color of a specimen is deteriorated so much that the original color can no longer be guessed. Note that in some cases an alternative to not coding at all may be to use certainty modifiers like 'perhaps' to make a tentative statement. (Note: no DELTA equivalent exists.)</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:BasicStatus>CannotBeCoded</ues:BasicStatus>
              <ues:InformationInSource>Exists</ues:InformationInSource>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="DataWithheld">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Data withheld (exist in source of current document, but private or confidential).</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">§</Label>
              <Detail> (Note: no DELTA equivalent exists.)</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:BasicStatus>CodedSuccessfully</ues:BasicStatus>
              <ues:InformationInSource>Exists</ues:InformationInSource>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="UnivarAnyStatMeasureEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>UnivarAnyStatMeasure</Label>
          <Detail>Enumerated list of univariate statistical methods. The list is intended to be more complete than normally necessary at least in biological morphometrics. If you still miss some measures, please request additions in a future version of this schema. Note: No satisfying external ontology for statistical methods could be found; the statistics section of MathML 2.0 (statistics.xsd) seems rather incomplete!</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="ObserverEstLower">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Lower range limit (human estimate)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">-</Label>
              <Detail>Free estimate made by human observer for the lower range limit (no statistical sampling and calculation was used). This method is appropriate when it is known that the values are derived from experience with the described objects (perhaps from memory) or from scanning a sample of objects and measuring those objects considered 'typical'. This method is not appropriate for single measurements or for calculations based on statistical methods (which provide exact 'statistical estimates'). Compare also the 'UnknownMethod'-methods that are provided for legacy data.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Untere Grenze (Schätzwert, ohne Berechnung)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">-</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Freie Schätzung ohne Verwendung statistischer Probenahme und Berechnung.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="### This and the following methods cover non-statistical methods that are frequently encountered in taxonomic publications. They are specified with MethodClass = ObserverEstimate or UnknownMethod. Most other methods are implicitly derived from a generalized hypothetical 'StatisticalEstimate' method. ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>ObserverEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>LowerRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ObserverEstUpper">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Upper range limit (human estimate)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">+</Label>
              <Detail>Free estimate made by human observer for the upper range limit (no statistical sampling and calculation was used). This method is appropriate when it is known that the values are derived from experience with the described objects (perhaps from memory) or from scanning a sample of objects and measuring those objects considered 'typical'. This method is not appropriate for single measurements or for calculations based on statistical methods (which provide exact 'statistical estimates'). Compare also the 'UnknownMethod'-methods that are provided for legacy data.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Obere Grenze (Schätzwert, ohne Berechnung)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">+</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Freie Schätzung ohne Verwendung statistischer Probenahme und Berechnung.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>ObserverEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ObserverEstCentral">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Central or typical value (human estimate)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">centr.</Label>
              <Detail>Free estimate made by human observer for a single central or typical value (no statistical sampling and calculation was used). This method is appropriate when it is known that the values are derived from experience with the described objects (perhaps from memory) or from scanning a sample of objects and measuring those objects considered 'typical'. It is not appropriate for single measurements nor for calculations based on statistical methods (which provide exact 'statistical estimates'). Compare also the 'UnknownMethod'-methods that are provided for legacy data.</Detail>
              <Label>Mittlerer oder typischer Wert (Schätzwert, ohne Berechnung)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">centr.</Label>
              <Detail>Freie Schätzung ohne Verwendung statistischer Probenahme und Berechnung.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>ObserverEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="UMethLower">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Lower range limit (legacy data, stat. meth. unknown)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">-(?)</Label>
              <Detail>Lower range limit obtained by an unknown method (e. g. human observer estimate or some kind of statistical estimate). The range may, e. g., be mean plus/minus standard deviation, or a range estimate. 'Unknown' is important for legacy data where the statistical measure used is not known. If it is known that a measure is a human observer estimate rather than a defined value, the 'ObserverEstimate' methods should be used instead.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>UnknownMethod</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>LowerRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="UMethUpper">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Upper range limit (legacy data, stat. meth. unknown)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">+(?)</Label>
              <Detail>Upper range limit obtained by an unknown method (e. g. human observer estimate or some kind of statistical estimate). The range may, e. g., be mean plus/minus standard deviation, or a range estimate. 'Unknown' is important for legacy data where the statistical measure used is not known. If it is known that a measure is a human observer estimate rather than a defined value, the 'ObserverEstimate' methods should be used instead.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>UnknownMethod</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="UMethCentral">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Central or typical value (legacy data, stat. meth. unknown)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">centr.(?)</Label>
              <Detail>Central or typical value obtained by an unknown method (e. g. human observer estimate or some kind of statistical estimate). The central value may, e. g., be a single measurement, median, or arithmetic mean. 'Unknown' is important for legacy data where the statistical measure used is not known. If it is known that a measure is a human observer estimate rather than a defined value, the 'ObserverEstimate' methods should be used instead.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mittlerer/typischer Wert (genaue Definition unbekannt)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Mittl.(?)</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>UnknownMethod</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Min">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Minimum value</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Min</Label>
              <Detail>Absolute smallest value</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Minimum</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Min</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Der kleinste beobachtete Wert</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="### Minimum/maximum are generally semantically identical, regardless whether human observer estimates or statistical estimates have been used. They are therefore only provided as statistical estimates, and it is suggested that human estimates of minimum or maximum are treated as statistical estimates with unknown sample size. ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>LowerExtreme</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Max">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Maximum value</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Max</Label>
              <Detail>Absolute largest value</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Maximum</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Max</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Der größte beobachtete Wert</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperExtreme</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Mean">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mean (= average)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">µ</Label>
              <Detail>This is the normal, arithmetic mean.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mittelwert</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">µ</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Dies ist der normale, arithmetische Mittelwert.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="### This and the following are central measures: ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="HMean">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Harmonic mean</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">hµ</Label>
              <Detail>The harmonic mean (reciprocal of the arithmetic mean of reciprocals) is rarely used. Recommendation: if nothing specific is said about a "mean", it can safely be assumed to be an arithmetic mean.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Harmonischer Mittelwert</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">hµ</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Der harmonische Mittelwert (Inverses des Mittelwert der inverses Werte) wird nur selten verwendet. Empfehlung: wenn keine genauere Angabe zu einem Mittelwert gemacht wird kann man davon ausgehen, dass es sich um den arithmetischen Mittelwert handelt.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="GeoMean">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Geometric mean</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">gµ</Label>
              <Detail>The geometric mean (antilog of mean of logarithms) is relatively rarely used. Recommendation: if nothing specific is said about a "mean", it can safely be assumed to be an arithmetic mean.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Geometrischer Mittelwert</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">gµ</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Der geometrische Mittelwert (Umkehrlogarithmus des Mittelwertes der logarithmierten Werte) wird nur sehr selten verwendet. Empfehlung: Wenn keine genauere Angabe zu einem Mittelwert gemacht wird kann man davon ausgehen, dass es sich um den arithmetischen Mittelwert handelt.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Mode">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mode</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">mode</Label>
              <Detail>The value or value class with the highest frequency (most frequently occurring). Applicable only to unimodal distributions.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Modus</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">mod.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Median">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Median</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">med.</Label>
              <Detail>The median is the 50 % percentile, i.e. 50% of the sampled values are smaller and the rest is larger than this value.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Median (Zentralwert)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">med.</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Der Median ist das 50% Quantil, d.h. 50% der Werte sind kleiner, und ebenso viele größer als dieser Wert.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="Note that the median is identical to a percentile with measure parameter 50%. Since percentiles have been split into upper and lower range limits, this is not possible, however. ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="InterqMean">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Interquartile mean (= average)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">IQM</Label>
              <Detail>A truncated arithmetic mean, calculated only from those values that lie between 25 and 75% of sample values. This reduces the dependency of the mean on outliers and measurement errors.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Interquartilsmittelwert</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">IQM</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Der arithmentische Mittelwert berechnet auf der Basis der in das symmetrische Intervall um den Median (= 50% der Beobachtungen) fallenden Werten.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="### End of central measures. ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>CentralMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Var">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Variance (sample, df = n-1)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Var.</Label>
              <Detail>Variance based on a sample; calculated with n-1 (n = sample size) degrees of freedom. This is the "normal" variance used in almost all cases. A variance is a standard deviation squared.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Varianz (Stichprobe, Freiheitsgrade = n-1)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Var.</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Streuung der Werte in einer Stichprobe, berechnet mit n-1 Freiheitsgraden (n = Stichprobenumfang). Dies ist die "normale" Varianz die in fast allen Fällen verwendet wird.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="### This and the following are variance measures. Note that most are dimensionless with the exception of the interquartile range. NOTE: Although not entirely true (the dimension of the variance is the square of the measurement unit), for practical purposes it may be treated as dimensionless. ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="VarP">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Variance (population; df = n; rarely applicable!)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Var. (pop.)</Label>
              <Detail>Variance of population, calculated with n (= sample size) degrees of freedom. Use this if the entire population of objects has been studied. Normally conclusions about the population are based on a sample that has been studied; in this case the "normal" variance with df = n-1 is appropriate.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Varianz (Grundgesamtheit, n Freiheitsgrade)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Var./G</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Varianz einer Grundgesamtheit, berechnet mit n (= Stichprobenumfang) Freiheitsgraden. In den meisten Fällen macht man Rückschlüsse auf die Grundgesamtheit anhand einer Stichprobe; in diesem Fall ist die "normale" Standardabweichung mit n-1 Freiheitsgraden zu verwenden.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalParameter</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SD">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Standard deviation (sample)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">s.d.</Label>
              <Detail>Standard deviation based on a sample, calculated with n-1 (n = sample size) degrees of freedom. This is the "normal" standard deviation used in almost all cases.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Standardabweichung (Stichprobe, Freiheitsgrade = n-1)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Std.Abw.</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Standardabweichung einer Stichprobe, berechnet mit n-1 Freiheitsgraden (n = Stichprobenumfang). Dies ist die "normale" Standardabweichung die in fast allen Fällen verwendet wird.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SDP">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Standard deviation (population; df = n; rarely applicable!)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">s.d. (pop.)</Label>
              <Detail>Standard deviation based on the entire population; calculated with n (= sample size) degrees of freedom. Use this if the entire population of objects has been studied. Normally conclusions about the population are based on a sample that has been studied; in this case the "normal" std. dev. with df = n-1 is appropriate.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Standardabweichung (Grundgesamtheit; n Freiheitsgrade)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Std.Abw./G</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Standardabweichung einer Grundgesamtheit; berechnet mit n (= Stichprobenumfang) Freiheitsgraden. In den meisten Fällen macht man Rückschlüsse auf die Grundgesamtheit anhand einer Stichprobe; in diesem Fall ist die "normale" Standardabweichung mit n-1 Freiheitsgraden zu verwenden.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalParameter</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="MeanDev">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mean deviation</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">m.d.</Label>
              <Detail>The mean of the absolute differences from the arithmetic mean of values. The absolute differences are the positive, unsquared differences from the mean.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mittlere Abweichung.</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Mittl.Abw.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalParameter</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="MeanDevMode">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mean deviation from median</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">m.d.m.</Label>
              <Detail>The mean of the absolute differences from the median of values. The absolute differences are the positive, unsquared differences from the mode.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mittlere Abweichung vom Median.</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Mittl.Abw.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalParameter</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="CV">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Coefficient of variation (sample)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">CV</Label>
              <Detail>Standard deviation (based on a sample), divided by the mean. The values entered should not be expressed as percent, but converted to a true value (use '0.3' for 30%). According to Sokal &amp; Rohlf 1981:59 this is a biased estimate, which may be corrected, compare 'CVC'.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Varianzkoeffizient (Stichprobe, Freiheitsgrade = n-1)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">VK</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Standardabweichung einer Stichprobe (n-1 Freiheitsgrade) geteilt durch den Mittelwert.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ValueIsPercentage>true</ues:ValueIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="CVC">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Corrected coefficient of variation (sample)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">CVC</Label>
              <Detail>Corrected coefficient corrected by (1 + (1/4n)). Compare, e. g., Sokal &amp; Rohlf 1981:59'.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Korrigierter Varianzkoeffizient (Stichprobe, Freiheitsgrade = n-1)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">VK</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Varianzkoeffizient korrigiert mit (1 + (1/4n)). Vergleiche Sokal &amp; Rohlf 1981:59'.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="TotalRange">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Total range</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">TR</Label>
              <Detail>The maximum value minus the minimum value. Also often called "Range" without further qualification like 'absolute', 'total'. This measure can normally be computed automatically based on minimum and maximum. It will be manually entered, if minimum and maximum are not separately cited in a publication.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Gesamtdifferenz</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">TR</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Maximum minus Minimum.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="InterqRange">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Interquartile range</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">IQR</Label>
              <Detail>This is the length of a symmetric interval around median, containing 50% of observations.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Quartilsdifferenz</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">QD</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Dies ist die Länge eines symmetrischen Intervalls um den Median welches 50% der Beobachtungen enthält.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SEMean">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Standard error of mean</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">s.e.</Label>
              <Detail>The standard error of mean is defined as: "std. dev. / square root(n)" (with n = sample size)</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Standardfehler (Mittelwert)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">SF</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>VarianceMeasure</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SEVar">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Standard error of variance (of multiple samples)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">s.e.(var.)</Label>
              <Detail>This is not a variance measure of the mean, but a measure of the variance of the variance estimates.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Standardfehler der Varianz (bei multiple samples)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">SF (var.)</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Der Standardfehler der Varianz kann nur bei mehreren Stichproben bestimmt werden. Dies ist kein Streuungsmaß für den Mittelwert, sondern ein Maß für die Streuung der Varianzschätzungen!</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="(ReportingClass = Other because not variance measure of mean!) ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>Other</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Skew">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Skewness</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Skw.</Label>
              <Detail>Coefficient of skewness of a distribution, a measure of the degree of asymmetry of a distribution around its mean: &lt;0 if mode &lt; median, =0 if symmetric, &gt; 0 if mode &gt; median.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Schiefe</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Sch.</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Schiefe der Verteilung: &lt;0 wenn Modus &lt; Median, =0 wenn symmetrisch, &gt; 0 wenn Modus &gt; Median.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="### This and the following are other distribution measures (other than range, central, variance): ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>Other</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Kurt">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Kurtosis</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Kurt.</Label>
              <Detail>Coefficient of kurtosis of distribution, a measure of the "peakedness" of a distribution.  A normal distribution has a value of 0.263, larger values indicate wider, smaller narrower distributions.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Kurtosis</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Kurt.</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Exzess (Kurtosis) der Verteilung. Eine Normalverteilung hat einen Wert von 0,263, größere Werte zeigen zu breite, kleinere Werte zu schmale Verteilungen an.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>Other</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="N">
            <Representation>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Stichprobenumfang</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">n</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Die Anzahl der Beobachtungen auf denen die angegebenen statistischen Maße (Mittelwert, Standardabweichung, etc.) beruhen.</Detail>
              <Label>Sample size</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">n</Label>
              <Detail>The number of objects studied and on which the other reported statistical measures (mean, standard deviation, etc.) are based.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="### Sample size is in a class of its own! ">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalParameter</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>SampleSize</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>true</ues:IsDimensionless>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ConfIntervalLower">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Lower limit of {ParameterValue}% confidence interval for mean.</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">-CI{ParameterValue}</Label>
              <Detail>The confidence interval is defined as a range into which the true mean of the distribution falls with a certain probability. The parameter expresses the confidence level in percent. Typical values are: 99.9% (= 0.05% from left!), 99% (= 0.5% from left), 95% (= 2.5% from left), 90% (= 5% from left).</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Untere Grenze des {ParameterValue}%-Konfidenzintervalls für den Mittelwert</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">-CI{ParameterValue}</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" debuglabel="This and the following are statistical range measures:">
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>LowerRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>true</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ConfIntervalUpper">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Upper limit of {ParameterValue}% confidence interval for mean.</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">+CI{ParameterValue}</Label>
              <Detail>The confidence interval is defined as a range into which the true mean of the distribution falls with a certain probability. The probability is expressed in percent in a parameter called; typical values are: 99.9 (= 99.95% from left!), 99 (= 99.5% from left), 95 (= 97.5% from left), 90 (= 95% from left).</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Obere Grenze des {ParameterValue}%-Konfidenzintervalls für den Mittelwert</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">+CI{ParameterValue}</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>true</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="PercLower">
            <Representation>
              <Label>{ParameterValue}% percentile</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">-P{ParameterValue}</Label>
              <Detail>The {ParameterValue}% percentile is defined such that {ParameterValue}% of the observations are smaller than this value. Typical parameter values are 2.5, 5, 10, 15, 20, 25 (= 1st quartile), 30. Do not use 50; use the 'Median' measure instead!</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">{ParameterValue}% Quantil</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">-P{ParameterValue}</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Das {ParameterValue}%Quantil ist der Wert der größer oder gleich {ParameterValue}% der Beobachtungen ist.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>LowerRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>true</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="PercUpper">
            <Representation>
              <Label>{ParameterValue}% percentile</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">+P{ParameterValue}</Label>
              <Detail>The {ParameterValue}% percentile is defined such that {ParameterValue}% of the observations are smaller than this value. Typical parameter values are 70, 75 (= 3rd quartile), 80, 90, 95, 97.5. Do not use 50; use the 'Median' measure instead!</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">{ParameterValue}% Quantil</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">+P{ParameterValue}</Label>
              <Detail xml:lang="de">Das {ParameterValue}%Quantil ist der Wert der größer oder gleich {ParameterValue}% der Beobachtungen ist.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>true</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="TrimMean">
            <Representation>
              <Label>{ParameterValue}% trim mean</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">+TM{ParameterValue}</Label>
              <Detail>The arithmetic mean of the symmetric {ParameterValue}% interior portion of a set of data values.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>true</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SDRangeLower">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mean minus {ParameterValue} stand. deviation(s)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">µ - {ParameterValue} s.d.</Label>
              <Detail>Lower limit of a range calculated as mean minus standard deviations. The parameter ParameterValue (here {ParameterValue}) defines a factor with which the s.d. is multiplied before it is substracted from the mean. Typical parameter values are 1 or 2.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mittelwert minus {ParameterValue} Standardabweichung(en).</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">µ - {ParameterValue} Std.abw.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>LowerRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>false</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SDRangeUpper">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mean plus {ParameterValue} stand. deviation(s)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">µ + {ParameterValue} s.d.</Label>
              <Detail>Upper limit of a range calculated as mean plus standard deviations. The parameter ParameterValue (here {ParameterValue}) defines a factor with which the s.d. is multiplied before it is added to the mean. Typical parameter values are 1 or 2.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Mittelwert plus {ParameterValue} Standardabweichung(en).</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">µ + {ParameterValue} Std.abw.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperRange</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>false</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="MinOC">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Minimum; outlier corrected ({ParameterValue} std. dev.)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Min\{ParameterValue} s.d.</Label>
              <Detail>Absolute minimum value of sample, excluding outlier values more than {ParameterValue} standard deviations distant from the mean. Typical parameter values are 3 or 4.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Minimum; Outlier-korrigiert ({ParameterValue} std. dev.).</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Min\{ParameterValue} Std.abw.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>LowerExtreme</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>false</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="MaxOC">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Maximum; outlier corrected ({ParameterValue} std. dev.)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Max\{ParameterValue} s.d.</Label>
              <Detail>Absolute maximum value of sample, excluding outlier values more than {ParameterValue} standard deviations distant from the mean. Typical parameter values are 3 or 4.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="de">Maximum; Outlier-korrigiert ({ParameterValue} std. dev.).</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev" xml:lang="de">Max\{ParameterValue} Std.abw.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:StatMethodClass>StatisticalEstimate</ues:StatMethodClass>
              <ues:ReportingClass>UpperExtreme</ues:ReportingClass>
              <ues:IsDimensionless>false</ues:IsDimensionless>
              <ues:ParameterIsPercentage>false</ues:ParameterIsPercentage>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="UnivarSimpleStatMeasureEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>UnivarSimpleStatMeasure</Label>
          <Detail>An enumeration of univariate statistical measures supported by UBIF (esp. used by SDD). Compare also UnivarParamStatMeasureEnum, containing further statistical measures that use an additional parameter (for percentage of percentile or confidence interval, etc.).</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ObserverEstLower</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ObserverEstLower" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ObserverEstUpper</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ObserverEstUpper" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ObserverEstCentral</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ObserverEstCentral" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>UMethLower</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "UMethLower" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>UMethUpper</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "UMethUpper" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>UMethCentral</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "UMethCentral" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Min</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Min" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Max</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Max" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mean</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Mean" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>HMean</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "HMean" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>GeoMean</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "GeoMean" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mode</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Mode" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Median</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Median" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>InterqMean</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "InterqMean" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Var</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Var" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>VarP</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "VarP" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>SD</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "SD" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>SDP</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "SDP" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>MeanDev</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "MeanDev" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>MeanDevMode</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "MeanDevMode" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>CV</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "CV" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>CVC</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "CVC" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>TotalRange</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "TotalRange" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>InterqRange</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "InterqRange" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>SEMean</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "SEMean" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>SEVar</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "SEVar" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Skew</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Skew" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Kurt</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Kurt" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>N</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "N" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="UnivarParamStatMeasureEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>UnivarParamStatMeasure</Label>
          <Detail>An enumeration of parameterized univariate statistical measures supported by UBIF (esp. used by SDD). This enumeration is similar to UnivarSimpleStatMeasureEnum, but here a parameter value is supported. Abbreviation, Label and Details (within xs:documentation) may contain the string "{ParameterValue}". Labels are expected to become meaningful if this is replaced with the actual parameter value.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ConfIntervalLower</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ConfIntervalLower" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ConfIntervalUpper</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ConfIntervalUpper" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>PercLower</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "PercLower" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>PercUpper</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "PercUpper" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>TrimMean</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "TrimMean" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>SDRangeLower</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "SDRangeLower" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>SDRangeUpper</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "SDRangeUpper" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>MinOC</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "MinOC" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>MaxOC</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "MaxOC" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="AgentRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>AgentRole</Label>
          <Detail>Provides codes for roles like author, editor, photographer, advisor, or copyright holder. The roles and their codes used here are based on http://www.loc.gov/marc.relators/ (as of 2004/6 available at http://dublincore.org/usage/meetings/2004/03/Relator-codes.html). For example, the enumerated code "aut" for author corresponds to http://www.loc.gov/marc.relators/aut. The DublinCore Agents group is considering using the same codes (see e. g. http://www.loc.gov/marc/dc/Agent-roles.html), but as of 2004/6 the DublinCore Agents subgroup did not yet agree on a Creator/Contributor refinement as qualified DublinCore. Note that the roles selected here are a subset of the roles that are available in MARC. See second annotation for reasons of not using a union-design, which would be easier to maintain!</Detail>
          <Label xml:lang="x-internal">AgentRole</Label>
          <Detail xml:lang="x-internal">Technical note: It would be preferable to define the values in separate enumerations and define this as xs:union memberTypes="AgentCreatorRoleEnum AgentContributorRoleEnum AgentOwnerRoleEnum". However, whereas XML Spy accepts this, Stylus Studio and Xerces have problems in accepting that a member type of a union may be a restriction of the union type including this member. Furthermore, Xerces has problems in understanding that a union of two types, each of which is a restrictions of QName, may be a restriction of QName. Therefore, as of 2005-03, a long enumeration is defined here which is then restricted to shorter enumerations. - Gregor Hagedorn</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="aut">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Author</Label>
              <Detail>A person or corporate body chiefly responsible for the intellectual or artistic content of a work. This term may also be used when more than one person or body bears such responsibility.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="edt">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Editor</Label>
              <Detail>A person who prepares for publication a work not primarily his/her own, such as by elucidating text, adding introductory or other critical matter, or technically directing an editorial staff.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cre">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Creator in general</Label>
              <Detail>A person or corporate body responsible for the intellectual or artistic content of a work. The more specific type Author [aut] or Editor [edt] should be preferred.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ill">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Illustrator</Label>
              <Detail>The person who conceives, and perhaps also implements, a design or illustration, usually to accompany a written text.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="pht">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Photographer</Label>
              <Detail>The person or organization responsible for taking photographs, whether they are used in their original form or as reproductions.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ctb">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Contributor in general</Label>
              <Detail>Someone whose work has been contributed to a larger work, such as an anthology, serial publication, or other compilation of individual works. Do not use for someone whose sole function in relation to a work is as author, editor, compiler or translator.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="trl">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Translator</Label>
              <Detail>A person who renders a text from one language into another, from an older form of a language into the modern form, or from one audience-specific representation to one appropriate for another audience.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="trc">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Transcriber</Label>
              <Detail>A person who prepares a handwritten or typewritten copy from original material, including from dictated or orally recorded material.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="clb">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Collaborator</Label>
              <Detail>A person or corporate body that takes a limited part in the elaboration of a work of another person or corporate body that brings complements (e.g., appendices, notes) to the work.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="col">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Collector</Label>
              <Detail>A person who has brought together material from various sources, which has been arranged, described, and catalogued as a collection. The collector is neither the creator of the material nor the person to whom manuscripts in the collection may have been addressed.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="crp">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Correspondent</Label>
              <Detail>A person or organization who was either the writer or recipient of a letter or other communication.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="prg">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Programmer</Label>
              <Detail>A person or corporate body responsible for the creation and/or maintenance of computer program design documents, source code, and machine-executable digital files and supporting documentation.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="rth">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Research team head</Label>
              <Detail>The person or corporate body that directed or managed a research project.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="rtm">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Research team member</Label>
              <Detail>The person or corporate body that participated in a research project but whose role did not involve direction or management of it.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="res">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Researcher</Label>
              <Detail>The person or corporate body responsible for performing research.
</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="sad">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Scientific advisor</Label>
              <Detail>A person who brings scientific, pedagogical, or historical competence to the conception and realization on a work, particularly in the case of audio-visual items.
</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="pfr">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Proofreader</Label>
              <Detail>A person who corrects text (orthography, grammar).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="mrk">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Markup editor</Label>
              <Detail>The person or organization performing the coding of SGML, HTML, or XML markup of metadata, text, etc.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cmm">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Commentator</Label>
              <Detail>A person who provides interpretation, analysis, or a discussion of the subject matter on a recording, motion picture, or other audiovisual medium.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="rev">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Reviewer</Label>
              <Detail>A person or corporate body responsible for the review of book, motion picture, performance, etc.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="csl">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Consultant</Label>
              <Detail>The person called upon for professional advice or services in a specialized field of knowledge or training.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="own">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Owner</Label>
              <Detail>The person or organization that currently owns an item or collection.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="fmo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Former owner</Label>
              <Detail>The person or organization who owned an item at any time in the past. Includes those to whom the material was once presented. The person or organization giving the item to the present owner is designated as Donor [dnr]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cph">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Copyright holder</Label>
              <Detail>A person or organization owning the copyright of the material.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cpc">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Copyright claimant</Label>
              <Detail>The person listed as a copyright owner at the time of registration. Copyright can be granted or later transferred to another person or agent, at which time the claimant becomes the copyright holder.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="dnr">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Donor</Label>
              <Detail>The donor of a book, manuscript, etc., to its present owner. Donors to previous owners are designated as Former owner [fmo]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="dpt">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Depositor</Label>
              <Detail>A person or organization placing material in the physical custody of a library or repository without transferring the legal title.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="AgentCreatorContribRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>AgentCreatorContribRole</Label>
          <Detail>Union of AgentCreatorRoleEnum and AgentContributorRoleEnum, but no Owner roles. Technical note: currently this is modeled somewhat strangely as an xml-schema restriction of AgentRoleEnum (= union of all three basic role groups). This is a workaround for a problem Xerxes 2.6.2 detected by Jacob Asiedu! We hope that in the future the whole 'xs:restriction' below can be replaced again with the much more straightforward 'xs:union memberTypes="AgentCreatorRoleEnum AgentContributorRoleEnum"/' (= union of the two intended AgentRole enumerations).</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>aut</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "aut" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>edt</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "edt" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cre</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cre" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ill</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ill" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>pht</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "pht" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ctb</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ctb" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>trl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "trl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>trc</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "trc" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>clb</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "clb" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>col</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "col" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>crp</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "crp" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>prg</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "prg" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>rth</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "rth" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>rtm</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "rtm" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>res</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "res" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>sad</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "sad" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>pfr</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "pfr" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>mrk</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "mrk" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cmm</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cmm" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>rev</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "rev" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>csl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "csl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="AgentCreatorRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>AgentCreatorRole</Label>
          <Detail>Enumeration of roles supported for creator agents. See AgentRoleEnum for information about the MARC relator codes.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>aut</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "aut" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>edt</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "edt" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cre</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cre" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ill</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ill" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>pht</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "pht" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="AgentContributorRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>AgentContributorRole</Label>
          <Detail>Enumeration of supported roles for contributor agents. See AgentRoleEnum for information about the MARC relator codes.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ctb</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ctb" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>trl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "trl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>trc</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "trc" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>clb</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "clb" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>col</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "col" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>crp</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "crp" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>prg</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "prg" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>rth</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "rth" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>rtm</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "rtm" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>res</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "res" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>sad</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "sad" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>pfr</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "pfr" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>mrk</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "mrk" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cmm</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cmm" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>rev</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "rev" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>csl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "csl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="AgentOwnerRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>AgentOwnerRole</Label>
          <Detail>Enumeration of supported roles for owner/copyright agents. See AgentRoleEnum for information about the MARC relator codes.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>own</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "own" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>fmo</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "fmo" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cph</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cph" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cpc</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cpc" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>dnr</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "dnr" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>dpt</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "dpt" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="LabelRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>LabelRole</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing the kind of label text. These are currently highly constrained, but either additional values or free extensibility (by union of this enum type with xs:anyURI) are expected for future releases of UBIF.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Full">
            <Representation>
              <Label>full label</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">full</Label>
              <Detail>Free-form label text designed to be as concise and expressive as possible while remaining intuitive and (locally) unique. Depending on the object type, this label may often be called 'name' or a 'title'. The recommended length is less than 80 characters; longer text (up to 255 char.) is supported but human user interface software may be optimized for shorter labels. Text is recommended to be unique within dataset, object type, and language/audience combination. A full label may contain abbreviations but is not usually considered an abbreviated label itself. It should uniquely identify an object, but multiple full labels may exist. -- Examples: Agent 'Gregor Hagedorn, BBA, Berlin', 'G. Hagedorn, Biol. Bundesanstalt'; Taxon 'Ascochyta aceris Fuckel', 'Ascochyta aceris Lib.', 'Ascochyta aceris Sacc.' or 'Ascochyta aceris Saccardo'. -- Other standards: ~= DC.Title.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Short">
            <Representation>
              <Label>short label</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">short</Label>
              <Detail>Short label text designed to represent an object in user interfaces or reports (esp. in tabular format) where space considerations are more important than intuitive understanding or readability. The text short label may be context dependent and may contain unusual abbreviations that require knowledge of the full/concise label to be intelligable. The recommended length is less than 20 characters (including blanks); longer text (up to 255 char.) is supported but may not be readable in all human user interface designs. When missing, applications may attempt to abbreviate the full label, which may result in duplicate labels, however.  Text is recommended to be unique within dataset, object type, and language/audience combination. -- Examples: Agent 'G. Hagedorn'; Taxon 'Asc. aceris Fck.'.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Abbrev">
            <Representation>
              <Label>abbreviation</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">abbrev.</Label>
              <Detail>A label text abbreviated as far as possible while remaining unique within a dataset. When missing, applications may attempt to abbreviate the short or full label, which may result in duplicate labels, however.  Text is recommended to be unique within dataset, object type, and language/audience combination. -- Examples: Agent 'GH'; Taxon 'A.aceris' (assuming the dataset contains no other Genus abbreviated as 'A.' with a species epithet 'aceris').</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Token">
            <Representation>
              <Label>token/variable name</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">token</Label>
              <Detail>A highly constrained version of the label designed for exports to applications requiring very short and simple object names, such as fields in databases and variable names in phylogenetic or statistical analysis software like NEXUS or SAS, which often must be short, not having blanks or punctuation, etc. The application for which a token label is designed may be specified using a custom language value, e.g. 'x-SAS', 'x-NEXUS'. -- Examples: Agent 'GHAGE'; Taxon 'AscAceris'.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Sort">
            <Representation>
              <Label>sorting string</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">sort.</Label>
              <Detail>A string that results in a desired sorting order when sorted with a standard, case-insensitive unicode sorting routine. The most important problems addressed here are word or token order, leading articles, and quoting marks (see examples). Other problems (special locale-specific sorting rules for accented characters like 'ü'='ue' in German but 'u' in Spanish, 'rr/ll' sorted after 'r/l' in Spanish, or character ligatures may or may not be addressed, depending on the data available to the provider. Where the provider has a choice, it is recommended *not* to address these problems, since sorting may be desirable according to rules defines defined in the locale of the consumer, not the provider. Current unicode-based data handling software often provides sufficient locale-specific sorting rules for accented or ligature characters. Problem: The provider may have stored all-uppercase sort-strings. This is not recommened, but consumers should expect that the sorting string has this form. One consequence is that the sorting string, while the best available choice for sorting where provided, may not be suitable for labeling the data in a sorted list. Should a second label type ('sortreport'?) be defined for this purpose? -- Examples: Agent 'Duarte, Amália Mourinha' (pt), 'Pina de Morales, Ana Maria' (es).; Taxon 'Isoetes' for if preferred form uses 'Isoëtes' (as allowable under ICBN); MediaObject 'high plano, the' for image titled 'The "high" plano'. -- Other applicable standards: vCard:Sort-String</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="DetailRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>DetailRole</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing the kind of long 'detail' text. In contrast to label text, detail text to which these values are applied are not restricted in length. Note that the text length of detail text elements is not limited by the schema. It is, however, recommended that the length does not exceed 30000 characters because longer text may lead to interoperability problems. Currently the enumerated values are highly constrained, but either extension or free extensibility (by union of this enum type with xs:anyURI) is expected for future releases of UBIF. Note that a 'description' is usually presented instead of the object, and a 'caption' always together with the object. An 'abstract' may be presented instead or together with the object.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Description">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Description</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">descript.</Label>
              <Detail>Free-form text describing an object. It may summarize the information contained in the object (similar to an abstract) but may also inform about related information. -- Other standards: ~= DC.Description.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Caption">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Caption</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">caption</Label>
              <Detail>A special form of free-form description that is expected to be displayed together with the object (especially images, video, or audio formats). Caption as defined here is limited to a caption displayed together with the entire object (i. e. excluding timed captions/subtitles of audio/video objects). Frequently description and caption texts are identical, in which case providing the description is sufficient. Specific captions may contain, e. g., references to places or objects in the image such as 'in upper left corner ...', 'bar = 10µm'.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Abstract">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Abstract</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">abstr.</Label>
              <Detail>A special form of free-form description that is contains a condensed version of the object content itself. Detail text with role 'abstract' is commonly used in the case of publications. The main difference to a 'description' is that an abstract does not contain external or metainformation about the object. Its applicability is therefore more limited, but also the correspondence of the representation with the full object may be assumed to be larger.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Coverage">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Coverage</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">cover.</Label>
              <Detail>Free-form text describing geographic, taxonomic, or other coverage aspects of the object or data set. -- Other standards: ~= DC.Coverage.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="NormativeText">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Normative definition</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">norm.</Label>
              <Detail>Free-form text defining the concept of the object (applicable only to conceptual objects, not actual objects like specimens or books). Similar to description, but considered normative or translated-normative. Desirable external validation: only a single normative text should be without a "translatedfrom" attribute, all other should specify a translation source (and are "translated-normative", not "fully normative").</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="UnknownDetailRole">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Unknown</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">?</Label>
              <Detail>The role ('Description', 'Caption', 'Abstract') of long detail text is unknown.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="MediaRepresentationRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>MediaRepresentationRole</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing the object representation role a media object (image, audio/video, rich text) may have. </Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Iconic">
            <Representation>
              <Label>icon/thumbnail (presented inline, if possible)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">iconic</Label>
              <Detail>Small image or short audio/video resource to supplement, but usually not replace label text. Most media resources of this role will not be informative enough to represent an object without additional textual representation. Recommendation: Typically only a single icon image should be defined for each object; applications may not be able to display more than one. However, combinations of still image and audio resource should be expected by applications supporting audio resources.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Primary">
            <Representation>
              <Label>primary representation (presented inline, if possible)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">primary</Label>
              <Detail>Media object intended as a first class representation of the object, fully informative without additional textual representation. If multiple media resources of this role are defined for an object, all of these are expected to be available when making the selection decision.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Diagnostic">
            <Representation>
              <Label>representation optimized for selecting one out of several alternatives (presented inline, if possible)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">diagn.</Label>
              <Detail>A subclass of primary media object representations, optimized for being displayed in situations where a human user is expected to choose (select) among multiple instances. Typically the size, duration, or complexity of these resources will be less than in a primary resource. Examples: in a multi-access picture key, the human selects one or several states describing characteristics of a specimen to be identified, or selected one of several images representing the remaining taxa. </Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Secondary">
            <Representation>
              <Label>additional, secondary, or supplementary representations (available on request)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">2ndary</Label>
              <Detail>Media objects intended to inform the user rather on request. For example, a user interface might provide a single link/button to request additional information, or a short list of links allowing direct access to individual media objects. Examples are images of a character state in a specific taxon, which illustrates the concept, but does not expresses its circumscription.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Normative">
            <Representation>
              <Label>normative resource for a concept definition</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">normat.</Label>
              <Detail>Detailed information used to define a resource object. Examples are images or rich formatted text (glossary entry, a wiki page, or a taxon/species page). Note: abstract concepts (taxon, character, publication) or physical objects (such as specimens) itself may be identified by URI in Link rel="BasedOn". Reflexive usage: recording that The URI may be identical to a definition resource identified through this resource role (but is not required to be).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="UnknownMediaRole">
            <Representation>
              <Label>unknown</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">?</Label>
              <Detail>The role of the media object is unknown (explictly equivalent to not specifying a value for the role).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="LinkingRelEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>LinkingRel</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing the semantics of a Link uri. The vocabulary includes all values from IRPStatementRoleEnum. These are currently highly constrained, but future version may add either more values or free extensibility (union of this type with xs:anyURI).</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="LatestVersion">
            <Representation>
              <Label>latest version</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">latest</Label>
              <Detail>Link resolving to a representation of the latest (i.e. newest) version of the object at the time of resolution. This explicitly assumes that the result of resolution changes over time (non-persistent resource).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="PriorVersion">
            <Representation>
              <Label>prev. version</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">prev.</Label>
              <Detail>Link resolving to the previous version of the current object. [Not related to xhtml prev]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Alternate">
            <Representation>
              <Label>alternate</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">alt.</Label>
              <Detail>Link designating an alternate (substitute) representation for the object in which this link occurs. These representations may differ in language, format, level of detail, etc. All alternate representations are implicitly about the same abstract resource, and it is recommended to express the abstract resource using rel="about". [Closely related to xhtml 1.0 "alternate" recommended link type value.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SubclassOf">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Subclass Of</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Subclass</Label>
              <Detail>Generalization relationship pointing to the more general concept (i.e. this concept is a kind-of linked concept).
Example: 'teliospore' and 'conidium are both a kind of 'spore', a 'spore' is a kind of 'propagule'). In the context of phylogenetic analyses a distinction between "homologous" and "heterologous generalizations" may be necessary, this is considered out of the general scope here and may be implemented in external ontologies.</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="x-internal">INTERNAL NOTE: synonymous names considered: KindOf.</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SuperclassOf">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Superclass Of</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Superclass</Label>
              <Detail>Inverse of subclass of; generalization relationship pointing to the less general class.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="BasedOn">
            <Representation>
              <Label>based on</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">BasedOn</Label>
              <Detail>The current resource is based on information from another resource, in a way that is different from verbatim copying and different from the extension semantics associated with sub/superclass relations. Specifically, this includes concepts like "source", "origin", or "derivation". "BasedOn" is transitive, not symmetric, not reflexive. Persistence of the other resource is assumed. The current resource may have a similar or entirely different format than the one it is based on. Examples: 1) A record based on a physical specimen (which has a urn). 2) A reference record based on a publication that has a DOI identifier. 3) A character definition based on a standard character definition.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SameAs">
            <Representation>
              <Label>same as</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">SameAs</Label>
              <Detail>Two resources have same semantics, same creator, same presentation format, but are not necessarily bitwise identical (e. g., sequence of elements in a set changed). SameAs is transitive, symmetric, reflexive. Persistence of the other resource is assumed. Note that multiple URIs of the current object may be given in "current", but this designates these as equal alternatives. Citing only one URI in "current" and others in "SameAs" may inform about older, outdated URIs.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SimilarTo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>similar to</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">SimilarTo</Label>
              <Detail>Both resources (indepently created or of unknown derivation) are analyzed to be similar. "SimilarTo" is symmetric, reflexive, not transitive (problem of chaining). Whether a data consumer desires to make inferences on the weak "SimilarTo" relation or not is its own decision. In the case of character-based identifications, the built-in error tolerance mechansisms of the identification method will often allow doing so. Persistence of the other resource is assumed. Examples: 1) A character state may be (more or less roughly) equivalent to another in another dataset, although neither definition is based on the other. 2) Multiple images may be taken from the same object.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="IsDifferentFrom">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Is 
different from</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Diff. from</Label>
              <Detail>Opposite assertion to "SimilarTo". This asserts that two resources may appear related, but are not. "IsDifferentFrom" is symmetric, not transitive, not reflexive. Persistence of the other resource is assumed.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="PartOf">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Part of</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Part of</Label>
              <Detail>Indicating composition. Data may be part of other data (a), a physical object may be part of another physical object (b), or an abstract concept may be a part of another concept (c). Examples: plant = root/stem/leaf, leaf = base/stipules/petiole/lamina, etc.; medium preparation and inoculation methods are part of microbial growth rate measurement method.
PartOf is transitive, anti-symmetric, and reflexive (though is of theoretical use only). Detailed information on use case (a): A dataset may be a subset of a larger dataset; if a dataset is dynamically generated in response to a query it may either have a URI encoding the query or no URI at all (i. e. uri-attribute on object itself does not exist), but may want to publish the URI or its base-dataset; one purpose of this is that a publisher may want to inform indexers (crawlers) about a resolvable URI to the larger dataset, another to establish the status of archival data. - On use case b): A microscopic slide may be part of a specimen in a collection. On use case c): A method may be a part (step) of a composite method, an article part of a publication, a petal is a part of the plant flower).</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="x-internal">INTERNAL NOTE: synonymous names considered: PartOf, HasPart, ComponentOf and HasComponent, ComposedOf, CompositeOf, ParticleOf, Aggregation.</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="HasPart">
            <Representation>
              <Label>has part</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">has part</Label>
              <Detail>Inverse of the part-of relation, indicating the parts that something consists of. A book may have resources for chapters that are independently retrievable, a specimen unit may have subunits, a descriptive term like "ovate to elliptic" has the parts "ovate" and "elliptic" (the kind of composition being not defined here!).</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="x-internal">INTERNAL NOTE: synonymous names considered: PartOf, Contains, HasPart, ComponentOf and HasComponent, ComposedOf, CompositeOf, ParticleOf.</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="BackwardCompatibleWith">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Backward Compatible With</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Backw. Compat.</Label>
              <Detail>The linked resource (usually a prior version) is backward compatible with the current resource. Examples: A new species has been added to a genus. The old enumerated taxon concept is backwards compatible with the new one. Related to: owl:backwardCompatibleWith.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="IncompatibleWith">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Incompatible With</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Incompat.</Label>
              <Detail>The linked resource (usually a prior version) is incompatible compatible with the current resource. Examples: A categorical character with 3 states (which partion a continous value space) now has 4 states. The addition of the forth state not only extends the value space (as in adding "ultra-violet", which might be BackwardCompatibleWith), but changes the borders of the other states (as in adding "orange" between "red" and "yellow". Related to: owl:incompatibleWith.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Meta">
            <Representation>
              <Label>meta</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">meta</Label>
              <Detail>Link referring to a resource offering meta data or help (more information about the current resource, including meta data like copyright or licensing, links to other sources information, etc.). Compare IRPStatements with role="Copyright", "License", "Acknowledgement", etc. to express more specific relations. [Related to xhtml 2.0 "meta", but also to xhtml 1.0-2.0 "help" recommended link type values.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="IRPStatementRoleEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>IRPStatementRole</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing the kind of IPR (= intellectual property right) statements.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Copyright">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Copyright</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Copyright</Label>
              <Detail>Copyright information for the current resource (or statement that content is in the public domain).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="License">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Licensing conditions for the current resource.</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">License</Label>
              <Detail>Data may be distributed under a license. Placing data under a public license (e. g., Creative Commons, GFDL, OpenDocument) while maintaining copyright is recommended. (= DC.Rights.Licence). Example when used with Link: rel="License" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.5/"</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="TermsOfUse">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Terms of use</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Terms/use</Label>
              <Detail>Defines conditions under which the data may be analyzed, distributed or changed. "Terms of use" includes concepts like "Usage conditions" and "Specific Restrictions".</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Disclaimer">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Disclaimer</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Disclaimer</Label>
              <Detail>Disclaimer statement, e. g., concerning responsibility for data quality or legal implications.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="PrivacyPolicy">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Privacy policy</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Privacy</Label>
              <Detail>Information and assertion of policy how individual privacy rights are observed.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Acknowledgement">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Acknowledgement</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Acknowl.</Label>
              <Detail>An acknowledgement of support (e. g., grant money, help, review, permission to reuse published material, etc.)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="IPRDeclaration">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Declaration</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">Declaration</Label>
              <Detail>Other forms of IPR declaration not covered by other IPR links (e.g., database rights); also used in cases where an automatic converter can not decide whether a statements is copyright, licence, etc.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="SexStatusEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>SexStatus</Label>
          <Detail>
            #html:p#Codes for sex value in humans (clinical status) or animals. The codes are largely based on those defined in DICOM (Digital Imaging and Communications in Medicine, http://medical.nema.org/, Coding Scheme Designator DCM Version 01, PS3.16 Annex B, CID 7455) and ASTM E1633 (= "Standard Specification for Coded Values Used in the Electronic Health Record. Document Number: ASTM E1633-02a. ASTM International, 10-Nov-2002, 76 pages"). Additional codes specific to biology have been added.#/html:p#
            #html:p#An alternative standard is ISO 5218, which provides only four codes: "0 = Not known, 1 = Male, 2 = Female, 9 = Not specified".  The difference between 0 and 9 is: "(0) implies that the sex of the person is not provided in the personal details i.e. the data has not been supplied and sex cannot be ascertained from the data provided"; "(9) implies that the sex of the person cannot be determined for physical reasons, e. g. a new born baby". ISO 5218 contains fewer and less intuitive codes. For biological purposes many codes would have to be arbitrarily added. G. Hagedorn, 10. August 2004#/html:p#
          </Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Male">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Male</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">m</Label>
              <Detail>[= ASTM E1633: M, = ISO 5218: 1]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Female">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Female</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">f</Label>
              <Detail>[= ASTM E1633: F, = ISO 5218: 2]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="UnknownSex">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Unknown sex</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">?</Label>
              <Detail>No information regarding the sex is available (= "not recorded" or "not examined"). [= ASTM E1633: U, = ISO 5218: 0]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Hermaphrodite">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Hermaphrodite</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">h</Label>
              <Detail>An organism having both male and female sexual organs at some time during adulthood. General term, not differentiating between simultaneous or sequential hermaphrodites. [= ASTM E1633: H]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SimultaneousHermaphrodite">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Simultaneous hermaphrodite</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">sh</Label>
              <Detail>An organism having both male and female sexual organs at the same time during adulthood. [Not in ASTM E1633; = B in OBIS 1.0 http://www.iobis.org/FAQschema1.shtml]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Male2Female">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Male changing to Female</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">mc</Label>
              <Detail>The organism starts as a male, and changes sex to a female later in life (sequential hermaphrodite: protandry). Examples: seabasses (fish); many plant species; humans that underwent surgical sex change. This terms does not identify a phase in which an individual may be. [= ASTM E1633: MC]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Female2Male">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Female changing to Male</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">fc</Label>
              <Detail>The organism starts as a female, and changes sex to a male later in life (sequential hermaphrodite: protogyny). Example: Wrass reef fishes; some plants; humans that underwent surgical sex change. This terms does not identify a phase in which an individual may be. [= ASTM E1633: FC]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="HermaphroditeMalePhase">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Hermaphrodite, male phase</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">hm</Label>
              <Detail>Sequential hermaphrodite in male phase. [Not in ASTM E1633]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="HermaphroditeFemalePhase">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Hermaphrodite, female phase</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">hf</Label>
              <Detail>Sequential hermaphrodite in female phase. [Not in ASTM E1633]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="HermaphroditeTransitional">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Hermaphrodite, transitional phase</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">ht</Label>
              <Detail>Sequential hermaphrodite currently between sexes. [Not in ASTM E1633, but compare OBIS 1.0 http://www.iobis.org/FAQschema1.shtml]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="IndeterminateSex">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Indeterminate sex</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">i</Label>
              <Detail>The organism has been studied, but the sex could not be determined (e.g. in larval forms). Compare "ambiguous" and "unknown" sex.  [perhaps = ISO 5218: 9; perhaps = DICOM: code 121103, 'Undetermined'; compare OBIS 1.0 http://www.iobis.org/FAQschema1.shtml]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="AmbiguousSex">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ambiguous sex</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">a</Label>
              <Detail>The sex organs have been studied, but the result was ambiguous. Includes abnormal mixed sex situations like "gynandromorph" (e. g. an insect is male on one side, female on the other). Compare "indeterminate" and "unknown" sex.  [= ASTM E1633: A]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="MixedSex">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Mixed sex status</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">x</Label>
              <Detail>Multiple objects of mixed sex status (situation occurring in collections).</Detail>
              <Label xml:lang="x-internal">(X - Mixed sex - Requested by Walter Berendsohn).</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="BasicSexStatusEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>BasicSexStatus</Label>
          <Detail>Contains basic sex type codes, sufficient for recording human sexes in most administrative contexts (used, e. g., in the Agent type data interface)</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Male</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Male" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Female</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Female" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>UnknownSex</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "UnknownSex" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="AdditionalSexStatusEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>AdditionalSexStatus</Label>
          <Detail>Contains codes in addition to those defined in BasicSexStatusEnum that are necessary for animals and clinical sex descriptions of humans. Additional codes "S, I, HM, HF, HT" has been added to those defined in DICOM /ASTM E1633. On the other side, the DICOM /ASTM E1633 codes "MP = male pseudohermaphrodite" and "FP = female pseudohermaphrodite" are omitted here because they are limited to human sex and express a politically contentious perspective (see http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pseudohermaphrodite). See the UBIF type SexStatusEnum for a union of the enumerated values in this type and those in BasicSexStatusEnum.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Hermaphrodite</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Hermaphrodite" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>SimultaneousHermaphrodite</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "SimultaneousHermaphrodite" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Male2Female</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Male2Female" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Female2Male</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Female2Male" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>HermaphroditeMalePhase</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "HermaphroditeMalePhase" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>HermaphroditeFemalePhase</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "HermaphroditeFemalePhase" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>HermaphroditeTransitional</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "HermaphroditeTransitional" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>IndeterminateSex</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "IndeterminateSex" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>AmbiguousSex</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "AmbiguousSex" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>MixedSex</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "MixedSex" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonHierarchyTypeEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonHierarchyType</Label>
          <Detail>Defines the type of a taxon hierarchy (list of enumerated values to support application interoperability).</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="UnspecifiedTaxonomy">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Unspecified taxonomy</Label>
              <Detail>Conventional taxonomic or nomenclatural arrangement (this could be a PhylogeneticTaxonomy, a NonphylogeneticTaxonomy, or a mixture). In the absences of more specific information about a taxon hierarchy, this may be considered the default value.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="PhylogeneticTaxonomy">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Phylogenetic taxonomy</Label>
              <Detail>Hierarchy resulting from a phylogenetic analysis, regardless of whether the taxonomic conclusions are already implemented or not. This asserts a higher quality of the hierarchy.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="NonphylogeneticTaxonomy">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Nonphylogenetic taxonomy</Label>
              <Detail>A hierarchy explicitly proposing a non-phylogenetic arrangements (herbs, shrubs, small trees, large trees).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="SubsetFilter">
            <Representation>
              <Label>SubsetFilter</Label>
              <Detail>A hierarchy of type "SubsetFilter" is intended only for the purpose of filtering taxa for arbitrary purposes. It will often be a flat list, or a list of filter names, each with a list of taxa. Applications should not offer it as a choice when the user selects a hierarchy for displaying or reporting purposes. Note that conversely, the filter selection dialog in applications should not be restricted to hierarchies of type SubsetFilter. Note, however, that any hierarchy may be used as a filter to define subsets.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="IdentificationCertaintyEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>IdentificationCertainty</Label>
          <Detail>Identifications of an Specimen (object/unit) as belonging to a taxon concept may be uncertain. This is especially important in biology, where identification qualifiers like 'cf.' or 'aff.' are often used as part of the scientific name. The following enumerated list provides general categories not restricted to scientific organism names. Note: In biology additional expression is often expressed through the choice of placement of the certainty qualifier. For example, 'Echinonema ferruginea var. campestris' may be qualified as 'cf. Echinonema ferruginea var. campestris', 'Echinonema cf. ferruginea var. campestris', 'Echinonema ferruginea cf. var. campestris'. The first presumably means that the entire name is uncertain, but the infraspecific name may be appropriate, the second indicates that the genus is certain, the species uncertain, and the final that the species in certain and only the infraspecific rank is uncertain. To achieve this level of expressiveness, it is recommended that an additional data element 'IdentificationUncertainTaxonomicRank' of type TaxonomicRankEnum may be combined with an element of IdentificationCertaintyEnum. IdentificationUncertainTaxonomicRank should be optional and omitted to express that an identification is unknown, but the rank not known (e. g. in 'Echinonema ferruginea?'). In ABCD 1.44 a special rank with enumeration beforeName, beforeFirstEpithet, beforeSecondEpithet is used instead.</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="IdentificationCertain">
            <Representation>
              <Label>The identification is certain</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="IdentificationUncertain">
            <Representation>
              <Label>The identification is uncertain</Label>
              <Detail>In biology this is often expressed with the Latin 'cf.' (confer).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="IdentificationSimilarTo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>The identification names a similar object class.</Label>
              <Detail>In this case the identified object is considered very similar to those objects classified under the given name. Note that in contrast to 'Uncertain' this implies that the object most likely it does not belong to this class. In biology this is often expressed with the Latin 'aff.' or 'afin.' (affinis).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="IdentificationCertaintyUnknown">
            <Representation>
              <Label>The certainty of identification is unknown.</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="NomenclaturalTypeStatusOfSpecimensEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>NomenclaturalTypeStatusOfSpecimens</Label>
          <Detail>
            #html:p#This list is a first version of a constrained vocabulary to express typifying relations between taxonomic names and specimens (objects/units preserved in collections). Beyond those type categories explicitly governed by nomenclatural codes (Zoology, Botany, Bacterioloy, Virology), the list also includes some additional type status terms. These categories may be helpful when interpreting the original circumscription (topotypes, ex-types), but do not have the same binding status as terms governed by the nomenclatural codes. The enumeration attempts to strike a balance between listing all possible terms, and remaining comprehensible. In general, including too many terms was considered less problematic than omitting terms. Applications may easily select a subset for presentation in their user interface.#/html:p#
            #html:p#This list is intended as a first version and it is hoped that in the review process through TDWG it will achieve sufficient maturity to be truly useful. It is expected that over time revisions will have to be made. Please use the WIKI (http://wiki.tdwg.org/twiki/bin/view/UBIF/NomenclaturalTypeStatusOfSpecimensDiscussion) to discuss the current list and the lists of synonymous, doubtful, or excluded type terms provided therein.#/html:p#
            #html:p#Some background information: A type provides the objective standard of reference to determine the application of a taxon name. The type status of a specimen is only meaningful in combination with the name that is being typified (a specimen may have been designated type for multiple names in different publications). The type status of an object may be designated in the original description of a scientific name (original designation), or - under rules layed out in the respective nomenclatural codes - at a later time (subsequent designation). -- For taxa above species rank the type is always a lower rank taxon (e. g., species for genus, genus for family). The type terms for this situation are not included in the enumeration. Ultimately, typication of all taxa goes back to physical type specimens, but this should not be recorded as such in data sets. The indirect type reference in higher taxa means that typification changes to the lower taxon automatically affect the higher taxon.#/html:p#
            #html:p#The exact definitions of type status differ between nomenclatural codes (ICBN, ICZN, ICNP/ICNB, etc.). The term definitions are intended to be informative and generally applicable across the different codes. The should not be interpreted as authoritative; in nomenclatural work the exact definitions in the respective codes have to be consulted. A duplication of status codes (bot-holo, zoo-holo, bact-holo, etc.) is not considered desirable or necessary. Since the application of the type status terms is constrained by the relationship of the typified name with a specific code, the exact definition can always be unambiguously retrieved.#/html:p#
            #html:p#The following publications have been consulted to determine the number of type terms that should be included and to prepare the semantic definitions:#/html:p#
            #html:ul#
              #html:li#Nomenclatural Glossary for Zoology (January 18 2000; ftp://ftp.york.biosis.org/sysgloss.txt; verified 17. June 2004)#/html:li#
              #html:li#ICBN St. Louis Code (http://www.bgbm.fu-berlin.de/iapt/nomenclature/code/SaintLouis/0013Ch2Sec2a009.htm; verified 17. June 2004)#/html:li#
              #html:li#Draft BioCode 4th version (Greuter et al., 1997; http://www.rom.on.ca/biodiversity/biocode/biocode1997.html)#/html:li#
              #html:li#Glossary of 'type' terminology (Ronald H. Petersen; http://fp.bio.utk.edu/mycology/Nomenclature/nom-type.htm)#/html:li#
              #html:li#Dictionary of Ichthyology (Brian W. Coad and Don E. McAllister, 2004; http://www.briancoad.com/Dictionary/introduction.htm)#/html:li#
              #html:li#A useful resource that was not available when writing this proposal might be: Hawksworth, D.L., W.G. Chaloner, O. Krauss, J. McNeill, M.A. Mayo, D.H. Nicolson, P.H.A. Sneath, R.P. Trehane and P.K. Tubbs. 1994. A draft Glossary of terms used in Bionomenclature. (IUBS Monogr. 9) International Union of Biological Sciences, Paris. 74 pp.#/html:li#
            #/html:ul#
            #html:p#"not a type" was added from the enumeration published in TaxonConceptSchema v 0.8 by J. Kennedy &amp; Robert Kukla in October 2004#/html:p#
            #html:p#Dr. Miguel A. Alonso-Zarazaga and Dr. Walter Gams are thanked for review and help. - Gregor Hagedorn, 13.7.2004-17.11.2004#/html:p#
          </Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="allo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Allotype</Label>
              <Detail>A paratype specimen designated from the type series by the original author that is the opposite sex of the holotype. The term is not regulated by the ICZN. [Zoo.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="allolecto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Allolectotype</Label>
              <Detail>A paralectotype specimen that is the opposite sex of the lectotype. The term is not regulated by the ICZN. [Zoo.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="alloneo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Alloneotype</Label>
              <Detail>A paraneotype specimen that is the opposite sex of the neotype. The term is not regulated by the ICZN. [Zoo.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="co">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Cotype</Label>
              <Detail>A deprecated term no longer recognized in the ICZN; formerly used for either syntype or paratype [see ICZN Recommendation 73E]. [Zoo.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="epi">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Epitype</Label>
              <Detail>An epitype is a specimen or illustration selected to serve as an interpretative type when any kind of holotype, lectotype, etc. is demonstrably ambiguous and cannot be critically identified for purposes of the precise application of the name of a taxon (see Art. ICBN 9.7, 9.18). An epitype supplements, rather than replaces existing types. [Bot./Bio.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ex">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Type</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from some kind of type material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="exepi">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Epitype</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from epitype material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="exholo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Holotype</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from holotype material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="exiso">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Isotype</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from isotype material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="exlecto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Lectotype</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from lectotype material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="exneo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Neotype</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from neotype material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="expara">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Paratype</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from paratype material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="exsyn">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Ex-Syntype</Label>
              <Detail>A strain or cultivation derived from neotype material. Ex-types are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="hapanto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Hapantotype</Label>
              <Detail>One or more preparations of directly related individuals representing distinct stages in the life cycle, which together form the type in an extant species of protistan [ICZN Article 72.5.4]. A hapantotype, while a series of individuals, is a holotype that must not be restricted by lectotype selection. If a hapantotype is found to contain individuals of more than one species, however, components may be excluded until it contains individuals of only one species [ICZN Article 73.3.2]. [Zoo.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="holo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Holotype</Label>
              <Detail>The one specimen or other element used or designated by the original author at the time of publication of the original description as the nomenclatural type of a species or infraspecific taxon. A holotype may be 'explicit' if it is clearly stated in the originating publication or 'implicit' if it is the single specimen proved to have been in the hands of the originating author when the description was published. [Zoo./Bot./Bio.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="icono">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Iconotype</Label>
              <Detail>A drawing or photograph (also called 'phototype') of a type specimen. Note: the term "iconotype" is not used in the ICBN, but implicit in, e. g., ICBN Art. 7 and 38. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="iso">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Isotype</Label>
              <Detail>An isotype is any duplicate of the holotype (i. e. part of a single gathering made by a collector at one time, from which the holotype was derived); it is always a specimen (ICBN Art. 7). [Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="isolecto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Isolectotype</Label>
              <Detail>A duplicate of a neotype, compare lectotype. [Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="isoneo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Isoneotype</Label>
              <Detail>A duplicate of a neotype, compare neotype. [Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="isosyn">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Isosyntype</Label>
              <Detail>A duplicate of a syntype, compare isotype = duplicate of holotype. [Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="lecto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Lectotype</Label>
              <Detail>A specimen or other element designated subsequent to the publication of the original description from the original material (syntypes or paratypes) to serve as nomenclatural type. Lectotype designation can occur only where no holotype was designated at the time of publication or if it is missing (ICBN Art. 7, ICZN Art. 74). [Zoo./Bot.] -- Note: the BioCode defines lectotype as selection from holotype material in cases where the holotype material contains more than one taxon [Bio.].</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="neo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Neotype</Label>
              <Detail>A specimen designated as nomenclatural type subsequent to the publication of the original description in cases where the original holotype, lectotype, all paratypes and syntypes are lost or destroyed, or suppressed by the (botanical or zoological) commission on nomenclature. In zoology also called "Standard specimen" or "Representative specimen". [Zoo./Bot./Bio.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="para">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Paratype</Label>
              <Detail>All of the specimens in the type series of a species or infraspecific taxon other than the holotype (and, in botany, isotypes). Paratypes must have been at the disposition of the author at the time when the original description was created and must have been designated and indicated in the publication. Judgment must be exercised on paratype status, for only rarely are specimens explicitly cited as paratypes, but usually as "specimens examined," "other material seen", etc. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="paralecto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Paralectotype</Label>
              <Detail>All of the specimens in the syntype series of a species or infraspecific taxon other than the lectotype itself. Also called "lectoparatype". [Zoo.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="paraneo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Paraneotype</Label>
              <Detail>All of the specimens in the syntype series of a species or infraspecific taxon other than the neotype itself. Also called "neoparatype". [Zoo.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="plasto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Plastotype</Label>
              <Detail>A copy or cast of type material, esp. relevant for fossil types. Not regulated by the botanical or zoological code (?). [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="plastoholo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Plastoholotype</Label>
              <Detail>A copy or cast of holotype material (compare Plastotype).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="plastoiso">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Plastoisotype</Label>
              <Detail>A copy or cast of isotype material (compare Plastotype).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="plastolecto">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Plastolectotype</Label>
              <Detail>A copy or cast of lectotype material (compare Plastotype).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="plastoneo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Plastoneotype</Label>
              <Detail>A copy or cast of neotype material (compare Plastotype).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="plastopara">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Plastoparatype</Label>
              <Detail>A copy or cast of paratype material (compare Plastotype).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="plastosyn">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Plastosyntype</Label>
              <Detail>A copy or cast of syntype material (compare Plastotype).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="syn">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Syntypes</Label>
              <Detail>The series of specimens used to describe a species or infraspecific taxon when neither a single holotype by the original author, nor a lectotype in a subsequent publication has been designated. The syntypes collectively constitute the name-bearing type. [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="topo">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Topotype</Label>
              <Detail>One or more specimens collected at the same location as the type series (type locality), regardless of whether they are part of the type series. Topotypes are not regulated by the botanical or zoological code. Also called "locotype". [Zoo./Bot.]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="type">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Type</Label>
              <Detail>a) A specimen designated or indicated any kind of type of a species or infraspecific taxon. If possible more specific type terms (holotype, syntype, etc.) should be applied. b) the type name of a name of higher rank for taxa above the species rank. [General]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="sec">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Secondary type</Label>
              <Detail>A referred, described, measured or figured specimen in the original publication (including a neo/lectotypification publication) that is not a primary type. [General]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="supp">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Supplementary type</Label>
              <Detail>A referred, described, measured or figured specimen in a revision of a previously described taxon. This is not formally considered a type. Provided as an alternative to "not a type" to express knowledge about material elsewhere presumed to have a more formal type status. [General]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="no">
            <Representation>
              <Label>not a type</Label>
              <Detail>For specimens erroneously labelled as types an explicit negative statement may be desirable. [General]</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="NomenclaturalStatusEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>NomenclaturalStatus</Label>
          <Detail>Controlled vocabulary expressing nomenclatural status of a biological taxon name. ### This needs urgently revision! Enumeration of possible values for nomenclatural status. (Source: initial LinneanCore.)</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="Rejected">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Rejected</Label>
              <Detail>The name is rejected (invalid, not accepted)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Fails">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Fails</Label>
              <Detail>The name fails the requirement test for an acceptable name (e.g. pre-starting-date names).</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Conserved">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Conserved</Label>
              <Detail>The name is accepted by means of an explicit conservation proposal</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Sanctioned">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Sanctioned</Label>
              <Detail>The name is sanctioned (a special form of automatic conservation used in ICBN for fungi)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Accepted">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Accepted</Label>
              <Detail>The name is accepted.</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="NomenclaturalCodesEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>NomenclaturalCodes</Label>
          <Detail>Enumeration of nomenclatural codes under which a name is considered valid. (Source: comparison of enumerations in ABCD 1.49 and first LinneanCore draft.) - Gregor Hagedorn</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Viral</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Viral" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>Bacteriological</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "Bacteriological" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Botanical">
            <Representation>
              <Label>International Code of Botanical Nomenclature, ICBN</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Zoological">
            <Representation>
              <Label>International Code of Zoological Nomenclature, ICZN</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="CultivatedPlant">
            <Representation>
              <Label>International Code of cultivated plants, ICNCP</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="Indeterminate">
            <Representation>
              <Label>Examples: ambiregnally named taxa can not be fixed to a code; to express the (pre-starting point) names on which the sanctioning mechanism of fungal names is based.</Label>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRank</Label>
          <Detail>
            #html:p#Enumerated codes to express the rank of a taxon (scientific organism name) in a taxonomic hierarchy. The list is intended to be interoperable between name providers for bacteria, viruses, fungi, plants, and animals. It is not assumed that in each taxonomic group all ranks have to be used. Individual applications may select appropriate subsets (which may be based on information given inside the enumerated values, see Specifications/BioCode-, Botany-, Zoology-, and BacteriaStatus). The enumeration attempts to strike a balance between listing all possible rank terms, and remaining comprehensible. For example, the "infra-" ranks specifically mentioned in BioCode have been included (although very rarely used), but the additional intermediate zoological ranks (micro, nano, pico, etc.) are not included. Whether the selection of infraspecific ranks (some informal ranks, esp. from bacteriology, may be missing!) probably needs some discussion. However, it is believed that this list may help to start developing data sets that can easily be integrated across the barriers of language and taxonomic traditions.#/html:p#
            #html:p#Not included in the list are the botanical "notho-" ranks, which are used to designate hybrids (nothospecies, nothogenus). It is assumed they can be generated from separate information that the taxon is a hybrid. ICBN §4.4 states: "The subordinate ranks of nothotaxa are the same as the subordinate ranks of non-hybrid taxa, except that nothogenus is the highest rank permitted".#/html:p#
            #html:p#The following publications have been consulted to determine the number of type terms that should be included and to prepare the semantic definitions:#/html:p#
            #html:ul#
              #html:li#The Berlin Taxonomic Information Model, MoReTax view (Berendsohn &amp; al., http://www.bgbm.org/scripts/ASP/BGBMModel/Catalogues.asp?Cat=MT#/html:li#
              #html:li#DiversityTaxonomy model version 0.7 (G. Hagedorn &amp; T. Gräfenhan 2002, http://www.diversitycampus.net/Workbench/Taxonomy/Model/InformationModels.html)#/html:li#
              #html:li#ABCD version 1.44, types HigherTaxonRankType and RankAbbreviationType, by W. Berendsohn, reviewed by D. Hobern#/html:li#
              #html:li#TaxCat2 - Database of Botanical Taxonomic Categories by Jörg Ochsmann, IPK Gatersleben; http://mansfeld.ipk-gatersleben.de/TaxCat2/default.htm#/html:li#
            #/html:ul#
            #html:p#Many thanks for review and help go to Dr. Walter Gams. - Gregor Hagedorn, 13.7.2004-17.11.2004.#/html:p#
            #html:p#Note: the list of all ranks is implemented as a union of all following rank subsets. Note that although BioCode has been used to define the partition into subsets, the ranks are not limited to BioCode but should be an interoperable superset of ranks used in Virology, Bacteriology, Botany and Zoology.#/html:p#
            #html:p#Technical note: It would be preferable to define the values in separate types and define this type as xs:union memberTypes="TaxonomicRankBelowSubspeciesEnum TaxonomicRankSpeciesGroupEnum TaxonomicRankGenusSubdivisionEnum TaxonomicRankGenusGroupEnum TaxonomicRankFamilySubdivisionEnum TaxonomicRankFamilyGroupEnum TaxonomicRankAboveSuperfamilyEnum". However, as explained in the annotation of AgentRoleEnum, Stylus Studio and Xerces have problems with type derivations involving union types. Therefore the current work-around was chosen.#/html:p#
          </Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition id="any_rank">
            <Representation>
              <Label>tax. of unknown or undefined rank</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">unknown</Label>
              <Detail>Use this if no information exists or can be deduced. If at least the rank group is known other values ("any_infrasp", "any_infragen", "any_supragen") should be preferred.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>(any)</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="any_infrasp">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infraspecific tax. of undefined rank</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">tax. infrasp.</Label>
              <Detail>Undefined ranks (using either no rank identifier in botany, or using greek letters or symbols like stars, crosses) occur in very old publications. Most frequently these are to be interpreted as varieties, but occasionally they are forms or subspecies (see Stearn, W.T. 1957: Species plantarum (Facsimile); Introduction. 1. London, p. 90-95, 160-161, 163). The interpretation of these cases requires taxonomic knowledge that may not be available at the time when data are parsed. Such lack of knowledge can be expressed using this rank identifier.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>tax. infrasp.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cand">
            <Representation>
              <Label>candidate</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">cand.</Label>
              <Detail>'Candidatus' rank is proposed in bacteriology for putative taxa, which could not yet be studied sufficiently to warrant the creation of a name with a known rank. (Murray, R.G.E. &amp; Schleifer, K.H.: Taxonomic notes: a proposal for recording the properties of putative taxa of procaryotes. Int. J. Syst. Bacteriol., 1994, 44, 174-176).</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>cand.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>Proposed</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="fsp">
            <Representation>
              <Label>special form</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">f. sp.</Label>
              <Detail>The ICBN does not formally cover formae specialis (art. 4, note 3). However, because of the economic importance of pathogenic f. sp., and since it is common practice to handle them as if the code would apply (i. e. priority usually observed, name quoted with author), they are included here.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>f. sp.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>forma sp.; fsp.; fm. sp.; f. spec.; fm. spec.; forma spec.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>used, but all ranks below subsp. are not covered by ICNP/ICNB, see Rules 5d and 14a. ##Check whether this rank is used indeed.</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>none</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subsubfm">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subsubform</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subsubfm.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subsubfm.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>subsubf.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional(?)</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subfm">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subform</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subfm.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subfm.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>subf.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="fm">
            <Representation>
              <Label>form</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">fm.</Label>
              <Detail>Form, race, variety are not subject to regulation in zoology; see ICZN Article 1.3.4</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>fm.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>f.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>secondary</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subsubvar">
            <Representation>
              <Label>sub-sub-variety</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subsubvar.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subsubvar.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>subsubv.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subvar">
            <Representation>
              <Label>sub-variety</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subvar.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subvar.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>subv.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="var">
            <Representation>
              <Label>variety</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">var.</Label>
              <Detail>Form, race, variety are not subject to regulation in zoology; see ICZN Article 1.3.4 Examples: Pinus nigra var. caramanica (= "P. nigra subsp. nigra var. caramanica"; Taxus baccata var. variegata</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>var.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>v.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>used, but all ranks below subsp. are not covered by ICNP/ICNB, see Rules 5d and 14a. ##Check whether this rank is used indeed.</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>secondary</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="pv">
            <Representation>
              <Label>patho-variety</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">pathovar.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>pathovar.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>pv.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>used, but all ranks below subsp. are not covered by ICNP/ICNB, see Rules 5d and 14a. ##Check whether this rank is used indeed.</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="bv">
            <Representation>
              <Label>bio-variety</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">biovar.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>biovar.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>bv.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>used, but all ranks below subsp. are not covered by ICNP/ICNB, see Rules 5d and 14a. ##Check whether this rank is used indeed.</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cv">
            <Representation>
              <Label>cultivar</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">cult.</Label>
              <Detail>The epithet is usually output in single quotes and may contain multiple words, see ICBN §28. Examples: Taxus baccata 'Variegata', Juniperus ×pfitzeriana 'Wilhelm Pfitzer'; Magnolia 'Elizabeth' (= a hybrid, no species epithet).</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>cult.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>Reference to 'Internat. code of nomenclature for cultivated plants'</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="convar">
            <Representation>
              <Label>convar</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">convar.</Label>
              <Detail>Used in cultivated plants (ICNCP), but deprecated, see 'Some notes on problems of taxonomy and nomenclature of cultivated plants' by J. Ochsmann, http://www.genres.de/IGRREIHE/IGRREIHE/DDD/22-08.pdf</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>convar.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>cv.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cvgroup">
            <Representation>
              <Label>cultivar-group</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">cultivar. group</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>cultivar. group</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="graftchimaera">
            <Representation>
              <Label>graft-chimaera</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">graft-chimaera</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>graft-chimaera</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infrasp">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infraspecies</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infrasp.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infrasp.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>infrasp.; infraspec.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subsp_aggr">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subspecific aggregate (= group, complex)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">aggr.</Label>
              <Detail>A loosely defined group of subspecies. Zoology: "Aggregate - a group of  subspecies within a species. An aggregate may be denoted by a group name interpolated in parentheses."</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>aggr.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ssp">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subspecies</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">ssp.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Pinus nigra subsp. nigra Homo sapiens sapiens</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>ssp.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>subsp.; subspec.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="sp">
            <Representation>
              <Label>species</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">sp.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Taxus baccata,  Homo sapiens</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>sp.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>spec.</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>primary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>principal</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>principal</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="aggr">
            <Representation>
              <Label>species aggregate (= species group, species complex)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">aggr.</Label>
              <Detail>A loosely defined group of species. Zoology: "Aggregate - a group of species, other than a subgenus, within a genus. An aggregate may be denoted by a group name interpolated in parentheses." -- The Berlin/MoreTax model notes: "[these] aren't taxonomic ranks but cirumscriptions because on the one hand they are necessary for the concatenation of the fullname and on the other hand they are necessary for distinguishing the aggregate or species group from the microspecies." Compare subspecific aggregate for a group of subspecies within a species!</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>aggr.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="any_infragen">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infrageneric tax. of undefined rank</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">tax. infragen.</Label>
              <Detail>A name that appear between a genus name and a species epitheton and is not clearly marked as series or section, or other may be assigned to this rank until the true rank can be assigned by a taxonomic expert.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>tax. infragen.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subser">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subseries</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subser.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subser.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>*</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ser">
            <Representation>
              <Label>series</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">ser.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>ser.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>*</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>secondary</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subsect">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subsection</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subsect.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subsect.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>*</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="sect">
            <Representation>
              <Label>section</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">sect.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>sect.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>*</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>secondary</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infragen">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infragenus</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infragen.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infragen.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>*</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subgen">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subgenus</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subgen.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subgen.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>*</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="gen">
            <Representation>
              <Label>genus</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">gen.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnolia Homo</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>gen.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>primary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>principal</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>principal</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infratrib">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infratribe</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infratrib.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infratrib.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subtrib">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subtribe</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subtrib.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subtrib.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-inae</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-inae</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-inae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-inae</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-ina</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered (but probably not in current use)</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="trib">
            <Representation>
              <Label>tribe</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">trib.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>trib.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-eae</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-eae</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-eae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-eae</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-ini</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered (but probably not in current use)</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>secondary</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="supertrib">
            <Representation>
              <Label>supertribe</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">supertrib.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>supertrib.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infrafam">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infrafamily</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infrafam.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infrafam.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subfam">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subfamily</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subfam.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnolioideae</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subfam.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-oideae</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-oideae</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-oideae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-oideae</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-inae</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="fam">
            <Representation>
              <Label>family</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">fam.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnoliaceae Hominidae</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>fam.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-aceae</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-aceae</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-aceae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-aceae</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-idae</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>principal</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>principal</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>principal</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="superfam">
            <Representation>
              <Label>superfamily</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">superfam.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnoliacea</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>superfam.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-acea</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-acea</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-acea</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-oidea; -acea</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infraord">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infraorder</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infraord.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infraord.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subord">
            <Representation>
              <Label>suborder</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subord.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnolineae Catarrhini</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subord.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-ineae</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-ineae</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-ineae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-ineae</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="ord">
            <Representation>
              <Label>order </Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">ord.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnoliales Primates</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>ord.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-ales</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-ales</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-ales</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-ales</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>principal</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>principal</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>principal</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="superord">
            <Representation>
              <Label>superorder</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">superord.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnolianae</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>superord.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-anae</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-anae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-anae</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infracl">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infraclass</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infracl.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infracl.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subcl">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subclass </Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subcl.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnoliidae Eutheria</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subcl.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-idae [proposed; Stackebrandt, E., Rainey, F.A. &amp; Ward-Rainey, N.L.: Proposal for a new hierarchic classification system, Actinobacteria classis nov. Int. J. Syst. Bacteriol., 1997, 47, 479-491.]</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-idae</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-phycidae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-mycetidae</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="cl">
            <Representation>
              <Label>class </Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">cl.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnoliopsida Mammalia</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>cl.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-ia [proposed; Stackebrandt, E., Rainey, F.A. &amp; Ward-Rainey, N.L.: Proposal for a new hierarchic classification system, Actinobacteria classis nov. Int. J. Syst. Bacteriol., 1997, 47, 479-491.]</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-opsida</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-phyceae</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-mycetes</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>principal</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>covered</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>principal</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>principal</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="supercl">
            <Representation>
              <Label>superclass</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">supercl.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>supercl.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infraphyl_div">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infraphylum (= infradivision)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infraphyl./div.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infraphyl./div.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subphyl_div">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subphylum (= subdivision)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subphyl./div.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnoliophytina Vertebrata</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subphyl./div.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-phytina</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-phytina</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-mycotina</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="phyl_div">
            <Representation>
              <Label>phylum (= division)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">phyl./div.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Magnoliophyta Chordata</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>phyl./div.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-phyta</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-phyta</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-mycota</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>principal</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>used, but all ranks above class are not covered by ICNP/ICNB</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>principal</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="superphyl_div">
            <Representation>
              <Label>superphylum (= superdivision)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">superphyl./div.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>superphyl./div.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="infrareg">
            <Representation>
              <Label>infrakingdom</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">infrareg.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>infrareg.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="subreg">
            <Representation>
              <Label>subkingdom</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">subreg.</Label>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>subreg.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="reg">
            <Representation>
              <Label>kingdom</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">reg.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Plantae Animalia</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>reg.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>principal</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>used, but all ranks above class are not covered by ICNP/ICNB</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>principal</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>principal</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="superreg">
            <Representation>
              <Label>super kingdom</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">superreg.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Eucaryota</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>superreg.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>additional</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>additional</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>additional</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="dom">
            <Representation>
              <Label>domain (= empire)</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">dom.</Label>
              <Detail>Examples: Archaea (= Archaeobacteria), Bacteria (= Eubacteria), Eukarya (= Eukaryota)</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>dom.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>secondary</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>used, but all ranks above class are not covered by ICNP/ICNB</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition id="any_supragen">
            <Representation>
              <Label>suprageneric tax. of undefined rank</Label>
              <Label role="Abbrev">tax. supragen.</Label>
              <Detail>This value indicates that the rank of a name is unknown. Compare "incertae sedis" which is commonly used as a replacement for a taxon to group all taxa whose position in the classification or phylogenetic tree is uncertain.</Detail>
            </Representation>
            <ues:Specification>
              <ues:PreferredAbbreviation>tax. supragen.</ues:PreferredAbbreviation>
              <ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>-</ues:AdditionalAbbreviations>
              <ues:SuffixBacteriae>-</ues:SuffixBacteriae>
              <ues:SuffixPlantae>-</ues:SuffixPlantae>
              <ues:SuffixAlgae>-</ues:SuffixAlgae>
              <ues:SuffixFungi>-</ues:SuffixFungi>
              <ues:SuffixAnimalia>-</ues:SuffixAnimalia>
              <ues:BioCodeStatus>-</ues:BioCodeStatus>
              <ues:BacteriaStatus>-</ues:BacteriaStatus>
              <ues:BotanyStatus>-</ues:BotanyStatus>
              <ues:ZoologyStatus>-</ues:ZoologyStatus>
            </ues:Specification>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankBelowSubspeciesEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRankBelowSubspecies</Label>
          <Detail>Subset of ranks; equivalent to BioCode "infra-subspecfic", i.e. below the species group</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>any_infrasp</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "any_infrasp" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cand</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cand" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>fsp</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "fsp" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subsubfm</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subsubfm" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subfm</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subfm" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>fm</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "fm" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subsubvar</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subsubvar" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subvar</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subvar" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>var</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "var" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>pv</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "pv" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>bv</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "bv" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cv</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cv" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>convar</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "convar" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cvgroup</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cvgroup" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>graftchimaera</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "graftchimaera" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infrasp</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infrasp" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankSpeciesGroupEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRankSpeciesGroup</Label>
          <Detail>Subset of ranks; equivalent to BioCode "species group", i.e. only species and subspecies</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subsp_aggr</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subsp_aggr" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ssp</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ssp" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>sp</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "sp" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankGenusSubdivisionEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRankGenusSubdivision</Label>
          <Detail>Subset of ranks; equivalent to BioCode ""subdivision of a genus" ", i.e. all ranks between genus and species group (i.e. not including subgenus and species)</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>aggr</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "aggr" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>any_infragen</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "any_infragen" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subser</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subser" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ser</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ser" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subsect</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subsect" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>sect</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "sect" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankGenusGroupEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRankGenusGroup</Label>
          <Detail>Subset of ranks; equivalent to BioCode "genus group", i.e. infragenus to genus</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infragen</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infragen" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subgen</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subgen" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>gen</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "gen" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankFamilySubdivisionEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRankFamilySubdivision</Label>
          <Detail>Subset of ranks; equivalent to BioCode "subdivision of a family", i.e. ranks between genus group and family group</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infratrib</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infratrib" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subtrib</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subtrib" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>trib</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "trib" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>supertrib</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "supertrib" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankFamilyGroupEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRankFamilyGroup</Label>
          <Detail>Subset of ranks; equivalent to BioCode "family group", i.e. infrafamily to superfamily</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infrafam</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infrafam" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subfam</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subfam" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>fam</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "fam" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>superfam</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "superfam" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
      <DescriptiveConcept id="TaxonomicRankAboveSuperfamilyEnum">
        <Representation>
          <!--(label to entire enumeration to support documenting tools; most applications don't need this)-->
          <Label>TaxonomicRankAboveSuperfamily</Label>
          <Detail>Subset of ranks; equivalent to BioCode "suprafamilial". This rank group includes all ranks higher than superfamily (class, phylum/division, kingdom, domain)</Detail>
        </Representation>
        <ConceptStates>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infraord</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infraord" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subord</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subord" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>ord</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "ord" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>superord</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "superord" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infracl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infracl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subcl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subcl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>cl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "cl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>supercl</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "supercl" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infraphyl_div</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infraphyl_div" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subphyl_div</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subphyl_div" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>phyl_div</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "phyl_div" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>superphyl_div</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "superphyl_div" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>infrareg</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "infrareg" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>subreg</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "subreg" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>reg</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "reg" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>superreg</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "superreg" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>dom</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "dom" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
          <StateDefinition>
            <Representation>
              <Label>any_supragen</Label>
              <Detail>(see value "any_supragen" defined elsewhere)</Detail>
            </Representation>
          </StateDefinition>
        </ConceptStates>
      </DescriptiveConcept>
    </DescriptiveConcepts>
  </Dataset>
</Datasets>
